[SPEAKER_03] So I went to move a planter in my front yard and there was a skink under it and the skink wouldn't move.
[SPEAKER_04] I fixed it.
[SPEAKER_05] It's labeled properly now.
[SPEAKER_04] all seniors so some of them may be 18.
[SPEAKER_02] Yeah I think first of all teaching a research class sounds amazing and the limitations piece I feel like there's so like so many people that could come in and talk to a class about like what that actually looks like to what it means for me to do
[SPEAKER_05] I found a whole bunch of them.
[SPEAKER_01] Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01] I was looking at the toes, too.
[SPEAKER_04] I feel like I should be capturing this cover.
[SPEAKER_04] This guy has not fully developed.
[SPEAKER_03] He has gills, like an axolotl.
[SPEAKER_04] I'm just so excited.
[SPEAKER_04] He's like I need to see their limitations.
[SPEAKER_02] I mean honestly
[SPEAKER_02] Yeah, I know a number of professors, probably, I know some of them in the Ed school, but I can't see the people that would want to come and talk to you.
[SPEAKER_04] Yeah, I would love to have somebody who's history, history, psychology versus science versus media.
[SPEAKER_02] I guarantee, like, David's actually a really good person at just bold emailing professors.
[SPEAKER_02] And they're pretty responsive, right?
[SPEAKER_02] Biology department, English department, I guarantee.
[SPEAKER_05] I don't know if I got them.
[SPEAKER_01] Is that an F?
[SPEAKER_01] What are they referring to?
[SPEAKER_05] They're F?
[SPEAKER_05] I think we're ready, guys.
Too bad.
[SPEAKER_02] Can you teach, when you kind of teach a research-based
[SPEAKER_01] That's my focus.
[SPEAKER_01] I don't try to, dude, standards come secondary to me.
[SPEAKER_01] I kind of make up my own thing.
[SPEAKER_06] I try to capture your conversation.
[SPEAKER_01] Get some of that salamander water.
[SPEAKER_05] So it has one spot like on it's like
[SPEAKER_01] like on its bottom side, the ventral side.
[SPEAKER_01] And it has two more spots, two more spots closer to its tail, right where its hind legs are.
[SPEAKER_01] And those two spots are vertically placed, one behind the other.
[SPEAKER_01] So one's closer to the abdomen, the other one's closer to the hind legs.
[SPEAKER_01] And the one, like the first one, is basically just below the head where the front legs are in the middle.
[SPEAKER_01] Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01] So the blacks, the first black spot, so there's three of them, right?
[SPEAKER_01] Two closer to the... Three, two are closer to the tail end and one's closer to the head end.
[SPEAKER_05] Mm-hmm.
[SPEAKER_01] And then we have two beady black eyes on top.
[SPEAKER_01] And it seems from like the backside, looking top down on the... It's hard now.
[SPEAKER_01] Okay, so then on the top head, I see two lines.
[SPEAKER_01] Yeah, that two lines running kind of laterally along its backside or dorsal side.
[SPEAKER_01] And it has two legs.
[SPEAKER_06] Let's see if I can count the toes.
[SPEAKER_06] I see three toes.
[SPEAKER_06] Let me use this lens.
[SPEAKER_01] You can also, you want to peek?
[SPEAKER_04] It's so hard to see the toes.
[SPEAKER_05] Come on, show me a toe.
[SPEAKER_06] My arms got tired.
[SPEAKER_06] You want to take a look?
[SPEAKER_01] Here, you can do the rest.
[SPEAKER_01] You wanna try and see if you can count the toes.
[SPEAKER_01] Maybe I'm just vision impaired.
[SPEAKER_01] Yeah, like I was thinking three but then I thought I saw five.
[SPEAKER_01] Three in the middle and then two legs.
[SPEAKER_06] What?
[SPEAKER_03] Did you measure it?
[SPEAKER_05] I think it's thumbnail length.
[SPEAKER_03] You might not be ready yet, but there when you're ready.
[SPEAKER_04] No gills on neck.
[SPEAKER_01] Go to two.
[SPEAKER_01] Body brown or black overall may have light stripes or spots, but most of the body is dark colored.
[SPEAKER_06] Ours is light colored.
[SPEAKER_01] Go to four.
[SPEAKER_06] It's a dusky.
[SPEAKER_01] Okay, is body yellowish or golden, long and slender, two black stripes down back.
[SPEAKER_01] That'd be a blue ridge two-line salamander.
[SPEAKER_01] Or if body's reddish.
[SPEAKER_01] I don't think it's reddish.
[SPEAKER_06] Where is this supposed to be reddish at?
[SPEAKER_01] Just says body reddish.
[SPEAKER_01] So if it's reddish, you go to five.
[SPEAKER_01] Red, orange, purple, or brownish with black speckles over back.
[SPEAKER_01] Dark lines from eyes to nostrils.
[SPEAKER_01] Reddish to brown red, sometimes deep purple to blackish with black speckles all over the body, black chin, eyes yellow, or gold.
[SPEAKER_06] That one doesn't say eyes.
[SPEAKER_01] That's where I'm leaning.
[SPEAKER_01] But I don't know, you wanna look at its dorsal side, that back side again?
[SPEAKER_01] Two black stripes down the back.
[SPEAKER_06] I think there were lines, but I don't know if they're... Okay, let's look at, that's a good idea.
[SPEAKER_01] Maybe larvae will help.
[SPEAKER_01] Toes have black tips.
[SPEAKER_06] Tips of toes, same color as rest of toe and foot, go to seven.
[SPEAKER_01] Rounded snout gills are like finger rather than feathery plumes.
[SPEAKER_06] I'm reading the other options just to see if we can rule them out.
[SPEAKER_01] We don't see any guild, right?
[SPEAKER_01] We don't have guilds.
[SPEAKER_01] So it's past that stage.
[SPEAKER_01] So I think it is kind of like a adolescent, maybe it's hard.
[SPEAKER_01] They're tiny and sometimes not visible unless you view the salamander in water.
[SPEAKER_03] So I think ours is a little older because... I feel like that's a two line, because that's those two lines.
[SPEAKER_03] chosen to key it out, then you and your buddy may say farewell to your salamander.
[SPEAKER_03] Now to release your salamander, you're going to take it back to you.
[SPEAKER_03] Can folks pause conversation for a second?
[SPEAKER_03] I want to make sure you hear this first.
[SPEAKER_03] release your salamander because it is so important that we get them back in a really safe manner so when you are ready to release even if that's not yet you're going to take your bag and this even though it's holding the ph kit is going to stand in for my bag and i'm going to take my salamander back to the cone before i open the bag so that they you know don't jump out on the way
[SPEAKER_03] I'm going to kneel down by the cone, and I'm going to gently invert the bag and shake my salamander loose right next to the cone that's marking the place that I found them.
[SPEAKER_03] I am not going to pick up the rock they were under, replace salamander, and then put rock back on top because possible squish.
[SPEAKER_03] We're going to drop them off at their door and let them go home in their own time.
[SPEAKER_03] Then you can double check that that bag is empty before you bring the empty bag back to me.
[SPEAKER_03] You're going to leave the cone in place, so don't bring the cone back yet.
[SPEAKER_03] Leave the cone in place.
[SPEAKER_03] And so that we can take data from it.
[SPEAKER_03] So, yes, if you're still sketching or still feeding out, feel free to continue those.
[SPEAKER_03] When you're ready, you and your buddy may take your salamander home.
[SPEAKER_05] The Blue Ridge, if you agree.
[SPEAKER_01] Body yellow is your golden, long and slender, two black stripes.
[SPEAKER_05] I don't think it's long and slender yet, but it does have those two black stripes.
[SPEAKER_05] Yep.
[SPEAKER_05] Sure, you wanna return the...
[SPEAKER_00] Yeah, it's tiny.
[SPEAKER_00] Leave the cone we're leaving.
[SPEAKER_00] Well, you guys got a big one.
[SPEAKER_00] It's a little beefy.
[SPEAKER_01] What do you think it's called?
[SPEAKER_04] We don't know.
[SPEAKER_04] John's going to call in some experts to investigate it.
[SPEAKER_00] Oh, really?
[SPEAKER_00] Yes.
[SPEAKER_00] A problem?
[SPEAKER_02] Digestion?
[SPEAKER_01] Where was it?
[SPEAKER_01] There's like exacts in there like over here.
[SPEAKER_02] That's what there's a possibility it could be.
[SPEAKER_05] Is that a tart?
[SPEAKER_05] Mm-hmm.
[SPEAKER_04] You see it beating?
[SPEAKER_04] The color kind of changes a little bit.
[SPEAKER_05] Yeah, that's crazy.
[SPEAKER_03] Did you get it?
[SPEAKER_03] Did you capture it on your GoPro?
[SPEAKER_05] Oh snap.
[SPEAKER_04] I don't know.
[SPEAKER_01] Vincent, come a little closer with me.
[SPEAKER_01] number six get in there okay is it even still on that's the thing i don't know yeah it's on okay i forget that it's there sometimes
[SPEAKER_06] I know I did that.