We're all within our group back on the trail.
You heard that I am not outdoorsy, but I am a gardener.
Kind of crazy, isn't it?
But if you find your niche, you just start to roll with it.
I'm no hiker, though.
Hiking is not my life, but hiking is a great thing to do.
Everyone can find small trails, short trails, or you can be a biker and bike on trails that are for bikes only.
I think we're coming to our first checkpoint.
We have a traffic jam.
Always a traffic jam, that's what we're going to call it.
We see more out here.
A lot of nice looking forestry.
That is definitely worth gandering at.
We have a ride out tree trunk right here.
That has long since been gone.
We are now crossing up the rocks and going to our checkpoint.
Reach.
What do you guys see in this area that might have been different than your hike up?
Is there anything else?
Berries.
Okay, berries.
Let's focus.
We have this area of observation over here.
You can even see up there.
It continues on the sides, but we want you to focus on this little berry right here.
There's one there.
And then you guys are going to try to notice the difference.
It's got two.
Yes.
So what do you think is those two points?
Like what is it from?
And what could possibly be unique about that berry besides the two points?
Well it could be from... What do fruit produce?
Seeds.
Okay, so how many seeds do you think might be inside?
Two.
Okay, and question?
So how do you think it came to be that berry?
Like what would create that berry?
Like how would it be reproduced?
With the egg and the sperm.
A flower, okay.
So if there's two seeds, double fertilization like two eggs and two sperm.
So two
two flowers yeah two flowers and you can taste it it's edible and it's just kind of like it tastes like air yeah you're not gonna get nutrients from it i've eaten them before i don't need to eat them again it tastes like um you can find the citrusy air taste the two seeds though they are two seeds yeah and you can like individually like pop it out immediately
Yep.
And it's called Partridge Berry.
Partridge Berry.
So it looks like the next group's coming up.
That was all we had for you guys.
Thank you so much.
We loved it.
Yes.
Do you all want this back?
There you go.
It's all yours.
It's not snack time yet.
Up the trail we go.
That was the first checkpoint.
And as we walk, we're going to look at the
downhill, you can hear the river, the waterway.
I'm not going to walk that far down because I could topple and I don't have insurance that can cover all that.
So we're going to continue to trek uphill with my partners.
As you see over here, you see all the greenery that is being shown or being produced by nature.
We see some pine
Can you say a pine tree or something close to that?
That is up here.
That is not quite your Christmas tree, but you know, it could be something to take home if you so choose to.
But you have to hike to get it.
We have this interesting tree right here.
It looks like a twig, a tall twig.
It strikes your imagination.
Look at that imagination.
Look at.
Now we're getting to our second checkpoint as we cross the threshold of this trail.
OK.
We need you to touch this leaf and tell us what you feel.
It's a sensory station.
Yes.
Sensory station.
It's so soft.
It is soft.
It's like a silk blanket.
There you go.
This is, there's so much better than the other group.
They're very indirect.
Yeah.
They said it was a sensory.
It's all about our delivery.
But the underside is veiny.
Yeah.
Okay.
What kind of tree does it remind you of?
Reminds me of a maple.
I almost thought aloe.
Oh, aloe's a good one.
Because it's smooth.
Yes.
So you're right, maple, because it has these little guys.
I said tulip poplar because I didn't see these by the way she was holding it.
So that's a very special leaf you want to know how to locate.
It is indeed a maple.
It's a striped.
And how do we know?
Maple because on the bark there's these little stripe marks.
And so it is a safe leaf that you need if you are in need.
It's the Charmin of the Woods.
Charmin of the Woods.
That's why you guys did so great.
For the toiletries.
You totally picked up on the fact that it was totally safe.
Excellent, excellent job.
And the Charmin is free.
The Charmin is free.
I'm all sweaty.
Nobody in there.
So we just found some Charmin in the forest.
It cost you nothing.
Just make sure you have some hand sanitizer afterwards.
Or maybe even some hand wipes, you know, to wipe it.
Maybe a little shovel.
A little shovel too.
So you can distance yourself from the scent both
never mind cut edit restart you see where this fell down yeah and all this is new like all this is all this quick growing that has popped up yeah
Just because it topples is that does not mean it will not be an asset to nature.
That's right.
All these these become nurse logs.
Mm hmm.
You get stuck.
They're already doing it.
They've already got mushrooms all over.
My father in law is 60 and he was tied up with an extension
We're coming to our third checkpoint, I do believe.
After we looked at this nice set of toppled trees and whatnot.
Lots of downed trees.
These are really big leaves.
Why would a plant have really big leaves?
To get more sun.
Maybe because it's diffused light and it has to spread itself out to get light.
And like the stems are not woody and kind of light so they're probably quick to grow, fast to grow.
So we've got some other plants that there are a lot of.
Could it not also be a... Mushrooms are not plants.
They're actually a... Fungus.
A heterotroph as opposed to an autotroph.
Okay.
We're more closely related to fungi than plants are.
Wouldn't these plants serve as food for animals, too?
They would, for sure.
But we've got a lot of one type of plant growing in this area.
These little hourglassy things?
Yeah, these little hourglassy things.
That's a tulip poplar.
A tulip poplar, which is also apparently the state tree of Tennessee.
Did not know that.
I think I've been told that before.
And they get big.
They get huge.
They do.
There's actually a few of them right over there.
I believe that's one right behind Jen.
They are early on the succession list because they are fast growing with those nice broad leaves for lots of energy harnessing.
energy or sorry photosynthetic energy is uh they're very good at harvesting photosynthetic energy because of their large leaves there we go yes there's a coherent thought you hear that camera thank you a really big one of those things that we yeah those are the broadleaf plantain thank you appreciation
Do you know that bird?
I do not know that bird.
It's the loudest bird in the forest.
The Carolina Wren.
It's a what again?
Carolina Wren.
Oh, a Carolina Wren.
I call it the loudest bird in the forest because it is.
Look how little.
Hmm.
Making that big old noise.
Had some big lungs, I guess, that we can't see something.
So this section of the trail, what sort of new thing caught your eye as you were walking up?
Like a little white mushroom.
That's the thing.
Okay.
so we were tasked with having you guys find the beginning middle and end of the life cycle of this mushroom yeah okay and you find it in three different cycles if it's fruiting life so
Some of them are round and closed and some of them are open.
Is the opening part a phase?
Is that the final phase?
Here's an open one.
This is closed and that one's open.
Yeah, but then I think... There's a medium.
Yeah, so that's the end phase and the closed is the beginning.
What do you think the middle phase would look like then?
a little bit open yeah say it again this is the middle stage no this is the beginning beginning and then that's the end more like the end phases what would be the middle phase like this one right here with a little open i think that's a bug hole i think
A what?
A buckle?
A bug hole?
You know bug holes?
They're like muggles except bugles.
I thought you said buckle.
In the bug hole.
The bug hole?
No.
I don't see one.
Do you see one that's different than those?
So I kind of feel like this one is a middle phase.
See how it's kind of starting to go a little more translucent.
Oh and it's not quite as open.
It doesn't have those ruffly edges.
Right.
Cool.
And then we were also asked as you were looking what's one unique thing about this mushroom than other mushrooms you observed.
Where is it growing as grouped together as some?
Okay, so more individual, not quite as clustered.
Isn't this a small cluster right here of them?
You may pass.
That's where I discovered them.
They look thinner too.
Well, looks like they're small clusters, though, like here.
Yeah.
Mm hmm.
Fascinating.
Thank you all.
Thank you for the lesson.
So that was checkpoint, I think, three or four.
I'm starting to lose count.
but it's all good.
But we just learned about some mushrooms and the stages at what, uh, what they're in stage one, stage two or stage three and how they look at each stage, which is very interesting and mind boggling at the same time.
Ooh, look all the campground down there.
That's what that is.
There's a campground down there, it looks like, where you can put a tent up and enjoy safely, of course.
Oh, let me catch up.
All right, y'all.
Hello.
Your station in this city.
you are going to be sharing with lots of ferns around you're going to be sharing about this particular fern right here if you already know it hold it hold your tongue um what do you all notice about this fern there's some here you can look at it you can feel it pay particular attention to the shape that's a different one that's the kind that she's looking at right there
See the difference here?
I do.
If you were a scientist and you were already given a scientific name but you were charged with giving it a common name, what would you name this fern and why?
I might name it something having to do with a comb because it looks like a comb to me.
Okay, the comb fern.
um it almost looks like a tree like some of the shapes it is something like a tree i don't know what its actual common name is given to by some random person so the actual common name of this fern is the christmas fern so on to your point some people are like oh it looks like a christmas tree yeah another reason i've heard is that if you turn the fern horizontally
that the little leaves look like stockings hanging from the mantle on a fireplace.
So your task is to have people notice, wonder about the fern, give it their own common name, and then you can share its real name and a little bit about the history of, well, one reason why.
all right have fun make it your own there's also just i just noticed there's also about a year a skinny yearling bear right down there he's just drinking at the stream he's in the trees oh yeah it's like a big dog is it coming up here
Do we have a dog, a bow horn?
He's not going to want to have anything to do with us if we make a lot of noise.
Hey, Bear.
You're beautiful.
Go away.
Go on now.
We love you.
Stay away from people.
Good choices.
I didn't see you there.
Come on now, we love you.
Okay, wow.
All right, I forgot I had my binoculars.
I've got my binoculars right here.
This is not my station.
If you can just keep an eye and make sure they don't come back this way, then people can look at it as they are coming up the trail too.
If it starts coming up the hill, we're going to yell at it to go away.
So I guess we taught our lesson, didn't we?
Who's ready for a fern lesson?
Who's our group?
We are.
How old is that bear, though?
A little bit, it's okay.
Go for it.
Now do it.
When do you get to be a fern?
You can see ferns all the time.
We'll teach you really quickly and then you can go.
to it.
But they do.
But it's okay.
Because we're protected.
Maybe.
It's the root dance.
Exciting.
Where's his mom?
Let's not figure that out.
I just want to keep my eyes open, just in case.
Would you all like a little lesson?
Sure.
Are you out of the first three?
No, you're not.
You don't know where to go, huh?
No, not a long way.
I don't know how long.
So don't we teach them the lesson and they teach it to the next person?
No, no, we stay here.
And then we come up, they go on and we stay here.
So we're looking at ferns.
And there are a couple of ferns in this area.
We're particularly looking for one that looks like this.
Up here those are a little different you see the difference in them.
Yeah, so if you were a scientist And you were gonna come up with a common name For that fern I want you to look at it and look at its characteristics and see if you can figure out What you might?
Name it Christmas tree.
Why do you say Christmas tree the shape?
And where do you see the shape like?
in the overall strand that's what i was looking at or a fan or a palm oh feather palm that's a good one fan feather palm
OK, those are both good.
Do you know what that fern is actually called?
I mean, I don't know the scientific names.
Furnace, furnace.
Yes, exactly.
Many people call this a Christmas fern because of the reason you said.
And also, some people think these little individual petals look like a stocking on the mantle.
Nice.
okay because like at the bottom there's a little there's a little heel in the bottom and so that's how i can tell them the difference between these two i don't know all the ferns but i know that one and there's another fern called a maiden hair fern where the ferns are like in a little wreath like a fairy might wear around her head so i can remember those easily well if you want to stay and bear you're welcome if you want to move on you're also welcome to do that
The bear is totally this round.
I know, right?
Yes.
I figured we were that literally every one right here.
I kind of think we was going to stay here by ourselves with this bear, but never mind.
Ann would keep us safe.
I love that you think that's true.
All I know how to do is yell great things at the bear about itself.
That seemed to work.
I learned that from the Rangers.
You don't have to say terrible, horrible things in the bear.
It can't speak English, it turns out.
You just have to discourage it with noise.
Turns out it doesn't know its name.
No, it just needs to stay away from people.
You see the bear stood there, isn't he?
Still going away somewhere?
I talked all night about him shutting up for the next two.
OK.
Well, there we learned that these two did.
so they can go.
It graduated.
You have a degree.
Hi guys.
Hello.
Ferns.
So, um, as you see these ferns, you see this one in particular.
What's the first thing that comes to your mind when you see this beautiful fern?
It's got these nice little ridges, sharp leaves.
Okay.
They arch.
They arch, all right.
So if they do those things, what would be the name that you would give it based on what you just said?
Just a common name.
Doesn't have to be a Latin name.
Like someone's teeth.
Reminds me of sawtooth.
Sawtooth fern?
Jaws fern.
Do you guys have any names?
Okay, looks like an arrow.
Arrow, yeah.
Okay, arrow.
Especially this big one right here.
So can you tell that those are different?
Yeah.
Yeah, they're a different variety of fern.
And we're wanting to focus on just this one.
I mean, not that you were wrong, but like to notice the difference, right?
They would have different names, right?
Do you want to propose a name?
Feather Fern.
That's nice.
Close.
What is it?
Bird.
There's a holiday that you get out of school for a lot.
It's kind of cold outside.
There you go.
Nice.
Because it looks like a Christmas tree.
Yes.
And these individual leaves, some people say look like a stocking.
I can see that.
Like stockings.
Yeah.
Because it has a little heel on the bottom there.
So it has like a Christmas vibe to it.
It's kind of a Christmas vibe.
Christmas in July.
Yeah.
That's right.
Should we move?
Thank you guys.
So you have passed.
You graduated.
I still have John's binoculars, but he's chasing the bear.
No camera?
It died.
Again.
Sorry, we had some good blooper reels too.
So you didn't get to capture the bear down there?
No!
Dang.
Well I did.
Good.
Footage.
Yes, I'm gonna sell it.
$5 per second for narration.
Well, come on up.
We're looking at some ferns up here.
There's a couple different kinds of ferns out in here, and we're kind of focusing on these right in here.
So once you just take a look at them and see what kind of characteristics you see, how would you describe their leaves or their shape?
Flat.
Are they compound or simple?
No, they've got to be.
It's one stem.
So it looks like it's a multi-stem plant.
It's definitely got little serrated edges.
Yeah.
So if you're the science guy who finds these out in nature and it's your job to give it a common name, what are you going to name it?
Pointy plant.
It looks more like a... It reminds me of a feather.
Yeah.
But it's not soft, but it reminds me of the shape of a feather.
Well, they are actually called Christmas ferns.
Oh, okay.
Yes.
can see kind of the shape of the Christmas tree but also some people think like if you turn it sideways it looks like little stockings hanging from the mantle.
That's a stretch.
I mean maybe back in the days when people would hang socks like an actual sock rather than a stocking.
yeah because socks tend to hang more straight the stocking really has the heel right yeah yeah yeah you have to think old school yeah and that's all we have to teach you today is it edible not that i'm aware of does it have a smooth side and a fuzzy side
You prevented me from my dad joke, which is everything's edible once.
Well, you all have graduated.
We're going to have a bear delay is my prediction.
Yes.
It's going to be like 20 minutes before anyone else comes along.
I need everybody to share all their