[SPEAKER_08] an excellent picture of Virginia creeper versus poison ivy.
[SPEAKER_16] But one of the things that I've experienced people and I
[SPEAKER_04] Yeah, all right, so how did it go?
[SPEAKER_17] Were you able to find data in 10 minutes?
[SPEAKER_17] Yeah, absolutely.
[SPEAKER_17] Right, so we have time for that, right?
[SPEAKER_17] Can you take 10 minutes out of your time to gather data?
[SPEAKER_17] All right, one comment.
[SPEAKER_13] Yeah, I was saying it was nice to go out for 10 minutes and see how much I could actually collect, because normally when I think of 10 minutes, I'm like, oh, it's not really enough time to do anything.
[SPEAKER_05] which helped with the large biodiversity in the area.
[SPEAKER_17] I think it was like the guiding response, like, oh, I know what I'm looking for instead of just like coming out and it would be very ambiguous.
[SPEAKER_05] Yeah, qualitative.
[SPEAKER_05] We're like, hmm.
[SPEAKER_17] Yeah, no, totally.
[SPEAKER_00] Well, just setting parameters, right?
[SPEAKER_00] Scientific data should have some sort of repeatable parameters.
[SPEAKER_00] So how big of a space?
[SPEAKER_00] We had species evenness, so are we going to do all the species or are we going to pick a subset?
[SPEAKER_00] Yeah, totally.
[SPEAKER_00] Those sort of things, like setting up the parameters.
[SPEAKER_13] Yeah, and I also I also I liked the openness that it just said insects.
[SPEAKER_13] And so it was more about like going out and it made me explore a lot wider area of things.
[SPEAKER_13] And then I could come up with some questions about things that I discovered that I wouldn't have found if I had a more
[SPEAKER_02] So this is an example of how we would use an activity like this in the middle school classroom.
[SPEAKER_02] Jen and I have both done this activity this year focusing on the question of how do you know if you have a healthy ecosystem or not.
[SPEAKER_02] And so we would do something really similar to what y'all just did.
[SPEAKER_02] We would take the iNaturalist app on our phones or we have class sets of iPads to have
[SPEAKER_02] are as many examples of biotic living things in the school yard as they could in a short amount of time, 10, 15 minutes.
[SPEAKER_02] There is a certain level of time that goes into cleaning the data so that it looks nice like this.
[SPEAKER_02] be a really simple activity with.
[SPEAKER_02] The middle school level.
[SPEAKER_02] Like I said I teach.
[SPEAKER_02] Eleven and twelve year olds.
[SPEAKER_02] So when we're talking about graphing.
[SPEAKER_02] It's very simple.
[SPEAKER_02] It's very.
[SPEAKER_02] Two column.
[SPEAKER_02] Bar graph.
[SPEAKER_02] We would.
[SPEAKER_02] Give the students this list of.
[SPEAKER_02] Species.
[SPEAKER_02] And give each student.
[SPEAKER_02] One or two.
[SPEAKER_02] Different.
[SPEAKER_02] Data points.
[SPEAKER_02] So that they could then go and look and say is this native.
[SPEAKER_02] Or is this invasive.
[SPEAKER_02] And then.
[SPEAKER_02] impressed with how even my 11 and 12-year-olds can learn to use Google Sheets in the classroom.
[SPEAKER_02] We use Code App to make this graph on the bottom left and just compare if we have a really big invasive bar and a really tiny native bar, how could that help us answer the question of, is this a healthy ecosystem or not?
[SPEAKER_17] I like, Audrey, that you have to just take the sticky notes.
[SPEAKER_02] Yeah, so this is Jen's.
[SPEAKER_02] Jen, you want to talk about code?
[SPEAKER_02] actually is that when they get to middle school there's a really steep learning curve of them thinking that animals are alive but not knowing that grass is alive.
[SPEAKER_15] We assigned points to that.
[SPEAKER_04] Um...
[SPEAKER_04] Alright.
[SPEAKER_15] So at least on a middle school level, it really entices them into the learning, and then they're kind of hooked, and they're willing to go through this process.
[SPEAKER_15] Back in the day, when there was Facebook, I would do more of these little templates where we would do like social media profiles, things like that.
[SPEAKER_15] So going outdoors, using iNaturalist, finding something of interest, and then they would do a little research.
[SPEAKER_02] planned this beautiful lesson and we were going to have volunteers come from Discover Life in America.
[SPEAKER_02] We had so many people coming to take our kids on hikes, do identifications, and it poured rain the whole time.
[SPEAKER_02] And so we pivoted and did something more similar to this where we brought samples in and it was still a really great learning experience and they have these
[SPEAKER_01] So thinking about how we can take that like motivation that we've kind of all grow up with curiosity, right?
[SPEAKER_01] And I like, I'm really stuck on when I hear that kids don't like science, I'm really stuck on like, when did they decide to stop liking science?
[SPEAKER_01] It wasn't when they were like crawling around, like looking for bugs under rocks, right?
[SPEAKER_01] That's like a motivation piece that like, as a high school teacher, when I see a student and they're like looking at going to college and they're like,
[SPEAKER_01] I'm not a science person when they come to my classroom.
[SPEAKER_01] Since when or why?
[SPEAKER_01] You've been influenced by one teacher or maybe two out of the world of science.
[SPEAKER_01] That's such a small population size.
[SPEAKER_01] So maybe as we teach, we think about that too.
[SPEAKER_01] Based on our approach, maybe we're really influenced by the trajectory of that student.
[SPEAKER_01] So at the high school level,
[SPEAKER_01] I like to start off with these small little bio blitzes where students are like motivated to learn just by like interacting with things around them.
[SPEAKER_01] And then we make lists of all the things we find.
[SPEAKER_01] And then I have them write down some observations, right?
[SPEAKER_01] And then eventually they turn those observations into like questions they have.
[SPEAKER_01] So if we see a hole in a tree, maybe we turn that observation into a question.
[SPEAKER_01] Well, I wonder how many animals live in that hole in the tree, right?
[SPEAKER_01] And right there and then we have the foundation for a lab design, right?
[SPEAKER_01] And so this is the type of stuff we do at the high school level after we make those motivational
[SPEAKER_01] So after we come up with our research question, then we're like, okay, what kind of qualitative data can we collect?
[SPEAKER_01] What kind of quantitative data collect?
[SPEAKER_01] What will that look like, right?
[SPEAKER_01] Based on our observations we had outside, what could we hope to collect data on based on that?
[SPEAKER_01] And so they make a list of things that they could qualitative and quantitatively collect.
[SPEAKER_01] Then we go back outside and we see if that's viable in small little preliminary data plots.
[SPEAKER_01] Then we come back inside, they collect the data, you can go to the next slide, and we wind up with this huge data sheet.
[SPEAKER_01] And we spend time cleaning it up and then it winds up looking something like this.
[SPEAKER_01] And then I have the students,
[SPEAKER_01] use that research question to inform the direction of how they process that data.
[SPEAKER_01] So they aggregate it in however way they want to describe that data.
[SPEAKER_01] And so this process does take more than one day, right?
[SPEAKER_01] It takes maybe three days in homework.
[SPEAKER_01] If you go to the next slide.
[SPEAKER_01] So this is kind of like the final product here and here.
[SPEAKER_01] We wind up analyzing some of the raw data points.
[SPEAKER_01] is there really a difference between the means?
[SPEAKER_01] And how I get them there is on the next slide.
[SPEAKER_01] So after they do their second observation, I have all the students run these little tiny slide decks, and they talk about their research question, they go over all the basics.
[SPEAKER_01] What's your independent variable?
[SPEAKER_01] What's your dependent variable?
[SPEAKER_01] And then they think about all the control variables they gotta think of, and I have them draw out their procedure so they know what that sample size might look like, so they'll know what kind of materials they'll need,
[SPEAKER_01] and then have them make a preliminary data table for collection.
[SPEAKER_01] And they also start to envision what their graph should look like.
[SPEAKER_01] So they know exactly what direction they're going.
[SPEAKER_01] And following this, I can't remember what slide's next, but we wind up with the option to use many different
[SPEAKER_01] Sheets for data collection, data cleaning.
[SPEAKER_01] But there are also other options for how to present that data.
[SPEAKER_01] So this is using Google Sheets.
[SPEAKER_01] This is another program that Josh mentioned earlier called Data Classroom, which I really love.
[SPEAKER_01] And then there's another one that Cody will be introducing called Code App.
[SPEAKER_01] And I guess I wound up using Data Classroom.
[SPEAKER_01] I lean towards it because
[SPEAKER_01] is really descriptive, right?
[SPEAKER_01] But I guess in addition, this one costs money, and this one doesn't.
[SPEAKER_01] And this one also might require a little more skills and grappling from students, which also could be good.
[SPEAKER_01] And then, as you'll be introduced to CodeApp, it's kind of a mixture of both, is my position, and it's free.
[SPEAKER_01] Yeah, I think as a science teacher, when I started at the like 11th, 12th grade level, I was not prepared for the mathematics I'd be teaching.
[SPEAKER_01] I spent a lot of time in seeking out like Josh and other people in the community to help guide me along the way.
[SPEAKER_01] And I guess that's how I found myself here today.
[SPEAKER_01] So yeah, that's what we wind up doing at the high school level.
[SPEAKER_01] And I think the next slide we talk a little bit about
[SPEAKER_17] So this is, so once again, we have certain classes that lend themselves to gathering data in, you know, easier and more challenging.
[SPEAKER_17] So we have state standards, you know,
[SPEAKER_17] and water cycle, right, and looking at the balance of things and stuff like that.
[SPEAKER_17] The first time I did this it was January and we were freezing and we were all outside gathering data.
[SPEAKER_17] It's time for a little more meals.
[SPEAKER_17] all drains go to the river, you know.
[SPEAKER_15] When I have my students go outside, they identify CC.
[SPEAKER_15] They even came out and brought like, waders for like, waders to wear, and that was like the funniest part.
[SPEAKER_05] make on Canva.
[SPEAKER_15] And then just another resource.
[SPEAKER_17] So I got Andrea.
[SPEAKER_15] Another?
[SPEAKER_02] going through the next two days.
[SPEAKER_12] So what's next on the agenda?
[SPEAKER_02] right there.
[SPEAKER_12] when y'all wrap up here.
you
[SPEAKER_17] They have a desk number, right?
[SPEAKER_17] So everyone in their group has one question to review whatever activity we were just doing, and then they share in their group.
[SPEAKER_17] So you're not having to answer all four questions, but you just answer one of them, and then you use each other for resources, right?
[SPEAKER_17] And then I think pair share is kind of the same way.
[SPEAKER_17] You got a desk number, and so
[SPEAKER_17] And then, so they all get to each.
[SPEAKER_12] Hey, one little public service announcement sorry to interrupt again but late breaking news the dorm is ready to be moved into so either right before or right after lunch that'll be
[SPEAKER_02] The question is, which one is your goal?
[SPEAKER_02] I want a three, connection to curriculum.
[SPEAKER_02] OK.
[SPEAKER_02] I'll just go ahead and suggest.
[SPEAKER_08] The things we've been talking about, ecology especially, but quantitative analysis especially, like taking data and analyzing it, independent variables, all of these things are
[SPEAKER_16] We've got a new bio one curriculum that we're trying to figure out.
[SPEAKER_04] I'm not sure how much I'm going to be able to do with that because it's a very regimented thing.
[SPEAKER_04] So we're trying to work this in.
[SPEAKER_08] But I also teach AP bio, which would be much easier to connect it to that because we'll have a lot more freedom and have a whole year to do it.
[SPEAKER_03] And so being able to, especially
[SPEAKER_08] I'm putting data analysis into putting that more into this AP curriculum for biology is a lot of experimental design, data analysis, and so being able to use that is really good.
[SPEAKER_02] I think I can put it in bio one, but it's just going to have to be a little lower level.
[SPEAKER_07] Okay.
[SPEAKER_06] the garden in seventh grade last year.
[SPEAKER_06] They already did it and they also worked in gardens with that same group that oversees them in elementary school.
[SPEAKER_07] So it's going to allow them to be able
[SPEAKER_07] So did they do it in the spring in seventh grade?
[SPEAKER_07] Well, seventh grade, yeah.
[SPEAKER_01] Folks, what's your barometer for learning more about iNet if you want to set up your class project?