Here's the trail after a brief conversation.
Just looking at some of it.
It's called the West Prong Trail.
We have some kid right here who's in timeout at the moment.
They put me in timeout.
see what happens when you don't follow expectations because i don't drop anything dumping water in his mouth oh so we hydrate our teammates okay you want to pour some water in my mouth one at a time just go buy a bucket who could squeeze squirt some water in my mouth
Feel a little weird, but we can do it Forest trees last part Positive behaviors only see here's a trail up here that we're not going on but
it is very far up you can see some of the forestry on the left you see tree trunks the roots of trees that have fallen you see fungus
that have grown on tree limbs.
You see other fallen trees, mushrooms, things of that sort.
See the crew down here as they get themselves prepared for the adventure of hiking this wonderful trail.
We're going in groups of twos, as you may have heard.
Reach one, teach one, I believe is what it's called.
And as we do that, we will be learning from each other.
and also using our teaching skills to instruct each other.
And that is the tutorial.
Probably everything for this video you can probably...
Yeah, you can edit it out or you can keep it.
But we are definitely going to have a fantastic time, even though that's not an educational word to use.
But we are currently in waiting.
So we're going to look around at some of the shrubbery, the forestry that we are in.
This trail right here, of course, is well traveled.
I'm not there by myself because it is not smart.
And we see a spider web right here.
Do not know what kind of spider that is, but I will not get close enough to find out because it is not healthy for a human.
We're going to back away and we're going to walk back down.
Oh, never mind.
We're going to stop here.
You see the algae on this tree?
It is nice or fungus or both.
Could be a mix of both.
I believe those are mushrooms, some of that sort.
Not mushrooms, but more probably fungus and whatnot.
So yeah, we're gonna walk back down to the bottom and show this huge park that we are engulfed in.
and to share with all of you who are gonna be watching the video.
So I will be back in a moment.
Oh, nevermind, scratch that.
I'm gonna stay on.
So I wanna go up a little more just because our team has not been called yet.
You see lots of forms of grass.
You see lots of vegetation that is growing about this forest, which,
is why they call the Great Smoky Forest or Great Smoky Mountains, rather.
Excuse my miss timing or miss naming it or misguiding the name I quoted.
But here we are.
So I'm going to stop here because I don't want to get lost in the forest.
But as we see, we have our other cohort on the film down below named Alicia.
And then we see that the rocks up here as part of the trail that we'll be walking.
I don't want to get too far to touch.
So I'm going to go about right here where we have
Of course, the tree trunk has been uprooted, most likely by storm or just nature.
As you can see, you can see how the roots have started turning into a different vegetation now that has been toppled, which means for the looks of it's toppled a long time ago.
And with that being noted and said,
it then turns into something else.
So it like grows, not grows, but it molds itself into nature as it sinks, as it starts to be engulfed in the soil beneath it and becomes a different asset to nature.
And up here, you see how the trail goes way up there, way up there.
It kind of has looks like it had like a wood railing to the right, down the camera to the left.
That's pretty cool.
Pretty cool.
Now we'll head back down before my group leaves me because I just may do that.
We don't want that to happen.
I'm going to come back down.
with society and I will reach out to you all shortly.