[SPEAKER_02] Here's some background information about us.
[SPEAKER_02] We've already introduced ourselves, though.
[SPEAKER_02] I think we can skip this slide.
[SPEAKER_01] I think we're good.
[SPEAKER_01] Yeah, I think we know each other.
[SPEAKER_05] All right, so everyone hopefully has a shoulder partner.
[SPEAKER_05] Designate who your shoulder partner is going to be, so make sure everyone has one.
[SPEAKER_05] Does everyone have a shoulder partner to talk to?
[SPEAKER_05] You've got two.
[SPEAKER_05] We need a shoulder partner if you don't have one.
[SPEAKER_06] Can you guys wait for your shoulder partners?
[SPEAKER_06] Or maybe give a high five to your shoulder partners.
[SPEAKER_05] These are the two prompts that we just want to discuss right now.
[SPEAKER_05] Just have you collected data with your students and
[SPEAKER_05] That's pretty much a yes or no.
[SPEAKER_05] And then like what do you do with the data?
[SPEAKER_05] So turn and talk.
[SPEAKER_05] Could you hold correct for just a second?
[SPEAKER_03] You get one minute.
[SPEAKER_06] Starting now.
[SPEAKER_03] We use trail hands and we do live.
[SPEAKER_03] So we do collect on, like, what do we, like, this past fall semester more slow than we've ever trapped and I had the pleasure of writing it.
[SPEAKER_05] That is never happened in 20 years.
[SPEAKER_05] That is great.
[SPEAKER_03] I mean, literally, we have never, and normally when we trap scum, it's spring semester more so than fall semester.
[SPEAKER_03] I don't.
[SPEAKER_03] The fact that we had so many, to the point that I'm thinking of setting the charts and keeping them open, because it was just too much time to release them.
[SPEAKER_03] It was brave.
[SPEAKER_03] All right.
[SPEAKER_05] So we'll do just two people share out.
[SPEAKER_05] First of all, check out this art over here that I just noticed.
[SPEAKER_05] Because they put that floor down to cover it up.
[SPEAKER_05] Does anyone know who did that?
[SPEAKER_02] Yes.
[SPEAKER_05] Who did it?
[SPEAKER_02] Well, this is our email.
[SPEAKER_02] over on the dorm steps, on the far steps, if you go up those steps up to the upstairs.
[SPEAKER_02] But it's Deborah Cook is her name.
[SPEAKER_02] She's a retired high school teacher from Ohio who has been our summer artist in residence at Tremont for the last 17 years.
[SPEAKER_02] She comes down every summer and does amazing calligraphy and marker art.
[SPEAKER_02] You'll see also on the flight board down in the dining hall,
[SPEAKER_05] All right, who has collected data with their students?
[SPEAKER_05] All right, that's a yes or no.
[SPEAKER_05] What do you do with the data if you have collected it?
[SPEAKER_05] I've collected data before and I did nothing with it.
[SPEAKER_05] But if we collected it.
[SPEAKER_05] So, the question is, what do you do with it?
[SPEAKER_01] Go ahead, Jen.
[SPEAKER_01] I'm volunteering her to share her story, because I thought it was a really good example of student gathered data.
[SPEAKER_03] Oh, we gathered the data.
[SPEAKER_03] So in the wildlife class, we're fortunate on our campus to have like a three and a half acre wooded lot.
[SPEAKER_03] And so with the wildlife class, we do a live trap and release unit.
[SPEAKER_03] And out of 20 years of doing this, never have I trapped more skunks in one semester than I did last fall.
[SPEAKER_03] to the point we've had to move where we store the traps because they smelled so bad.
[SPEAKER_03] I now have dedicated skunk shoes.
[SPEAKER_03] And so I'm wondering what in the world is going on that we had 16 skunks trapped within a three day period.
[SPEAKER_03] And obviously you can't mark them to see if you're capturing the same ones over and over.
[SPEAKER_03] But I'm wanting to know, I don't know what to do with that data other than figure out how not to get sprayed.
[SPEAKER_03] to release all of them safely.
[SPEAKER_03] But I'm really wondering, I've collected this data and skunks.
[SPEAKER_03] Why suddenly do we have so many to the point we're not capturing other animals at the rate that we normally do?
[SPEAKER_03] So that's what I've collected.
[SPEAKER_03] Now, what do I do with that?
[SPEAKER_03] Not get sprayed.
[SPEAKER_03] Top priority, but I don't know what to do with it yet, other than.
[SPEAKER_05] I love that you started with a question.
[SPEAKER_02] Yeah, you already did something.
[SPEAKER_05] You asked your question.
[SPEAKER_02] Why is this different?
[SPEAKER_05] Yeah, so what is happening?
[SPEAKER_05] What is different?
[SPEAKER_05] What is, yeah, totally.
[SPEAKER_05] So that's part of the process right there, is just asking the question, right?
[SPEAKER_05] And then like, what do you do with it?
[SPEAKER_05] Yeah.
[SPEAKER_05] Good call.
[SPEAKER_03] Yeah.
[SPEAKER_05] That's insane.
[SPEAKER_05] That's a good story.
[SPEAKER_05] Three and a half acres.
[SPEAKER_05] All right, so.
[SPEAKER_05] And who else?
[SPEAKER_05] What do you do with the data?
[SPEAKER_05] Does anyone do anything?
[SPEAKER_04] So in my eighth class, when we collect data, we'll do bubbles for survivorship curves.
[SPEAKER_04] Yeah, I've done that with them.
[SPEAKER_04] And we'll count cars, we'll file like the Shannon Wiener index.
[SPEAKER_04] We throw up your Google Sheets, graph it, see what it looks like.
[SPEAKER_04] Yeah, cool.
[SPEAKER_04] Analyze it from there.
[SPEAKER_05] Good, so using Google Sheets, definitely, yeah.
[SPEAKER_05] Most students are kind of comfortable with Google Sheets now, at least to some extent.
[SPEAKER_05] This problem, kind of work through it.
[SPEAKER_05] Some practice graphing, or like with mindless data, too.
[SPEAKER_05] Should like, hey, let's practice using Google Sheets and stuff like that.
[SPEAKER_05] Nice.
[SPEAKER_05] Cool.
[SPEAKER_05] Has anyone else done that bubble survivorship curve thing?
[SPEAKER_05] It's really fun to watch your kids try and keep the bubbles alive.
[SPEAKER_05] But yeah.
[SPEAKER_05] All right.
[SPEAKER_05] What else?
[SPEAKER_05] Anyone else want to share anything?
[SPEAKER_05] Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00] Using various salt solutions to figure out the starch content of the potato and graph it and try and figure out what the esotomic point is based off of just, you know, like four data points.
[SPEAKER_00] Nice.
[SPEAKER_05] Do you use mass?
[SPEAKER_05] Or what do you...
[SPEAKER_05] All right, anyone else?
[SPEAKER_05] We need to do the catalase lab with hydrogen peroxide and see how much foam is created and then we'll draft that.
[SPEAKER_05] Cool.
[SPEAKER_05] Do you feel the sheets?
[SPEAKER_05] They did it by hand.
[SPEAKER_05] Okay, cool.
[SPEAKER_05] Nice.
[SPEAKER_05] Yeah, that's good to practice too.
[SPEAKER_05] All right.
[SPEAKER_05] I think we're good.
[SPEAKER_05] Let's roll.
[SPEAKER_05] Uh-oh.
[SPEAKER_05] There's another question at the bottom here.
[SPEAKER_05] What challenges have you encountered?
[SPEAKER_05] The challenges are getting the kids to know how to use Google Sheets and different things.
[SPEAKER_05] Absolutely, yes.
[SPEAKER_05] Technology.
[SPEAKER_05] Well, freshmen.
[SPEAKER_05] Freshmen, okay, yeah.
[SPEAKER_04] But even my upperclassmen are resistant to Google Sheets at first.
[SPEAKER_04] Like, until they do that first, like, formula row and they see all that calculation just magically happen and then they're, you know, kind of sold on it.
[SPEAKER_04] Yeah, yeah.
[SPEAKER_04] When they're fumbling through learning how to do the dollar signs to hold sales and stuff like that and all the magic that it takes, I just really resist it.
[SPEAKER_04] I'm like, I can hand-calculate this.
[SPEAKER_04] Quickly, I'm like, no you can't.
[SPEAKER_04] But I promise, just stay with me.
[SPEAKER_01] Right, right.
[SPEAKER_04] In biology, I just haven't had time to teach them.
[SPEAKER_01] Yeah.
[SPEAKER_04] I just don't have enough time today Well, I'm saying it seems like I was in chemistry.
[SPEAKER_04] We don't necessarily teach it either So it seems like by the time they get to my class of my first eight
[SPEAKER_05] Hopefully some of the tools and the processes that we go through will alleviate some of that.
[SPEAKER_05] So I know it's still learning curves and all of those kind of things with the students, but if we can learn it, they can learn it, right?
[SPEAKER_00] and a data sheet and say who does it first.
[SPEAKER_00] Oh look, I'm done with my 10th one.
[SPEAKER_00] You guys have even done your first, yeah?
[SPEAKER_00] Well look, we're done.
[SPEAKER_00] You're still on the 11th one.
[SPEAKER_00] I'd be scared.
[SPEAKER_04] I got to run my back, kids.
[SPEAKER_05] All right, beautiful.
[SPEAKER_05] So we know there's challenges.
[SPEAKER_05] Obviously, that's why we're here, to try and progress through that.
[SPEAKER_05] So for sure.
[SPEAKER_05] All right.
[SPEAKER_05] You have a random piece of paper that Mr. Krebs gave you, David Krebs.
[SPEAKER_05] So you chose a piece of paper from a hat, right?
[SPEAKER_05] Hold on, our hat paper.
[SPEAKER_05] Your hat paper.
[SPEAKER_05] On the count of three, everyone open up their hat paper.
[SPEAKER_05] And on the count of three, say what your paper says.
[SPEAKER_05] One, two, three.
[SPEAKER_05] Salsa.
[SPEAKER_05] Beautiful.
[SPEAKER_05] So someone said the same thing as you in this room.
[SPEAKER_05] And you can find that person who said the same thing as you.
[SPEAKER_05] And hey, this is going to be very open-ended.
[SPEAKER_05] We're going to go outside for 10 minutes.
[SPEAKER_05] We're going to start a timer.
[SPEAKER_05] What sound are you going to make?
[SPEAKER_00] When I hoot like an owl.
[SPEAKER_05] What kind?
[SPEAKER_05] Can you demonstrate?
[SPEAKER_05] All right, let's go.
[SPEAKER_05] All you're going to do is find the other person, the paper who matches, right?
[SPEAKER_05] And then you're going to go outside, you're going to gather that data.
[SPEAKER_05] So you might need to journal.
[SPEAKER_05] You might need a phone if you're going to take pictures.
[SPEAKER_05] Whatever you want to do, draw pictures, bring back an artifact.
[SPEAKER_05] Don't go murdering things, right?
[SPEAKER_05] But we do bring back an artifact if you can, or you can draw some pictures and you're just going to collect data for 10 minutes.
[SPEAKER_06] And if you opened your paper and you have no idea what that thing is that's on your paper, feel free to wave one of us down.
[SPEAKER_06] We'd be happy to help you with it.
[SPEAKER_06] I know that my experience teaching 11-year-olds is a lot different, and I didn't know what species even this was until we were making this list.
[SPEAKER_06] So feel free to shout out if you need help.
[SPEAKER_06] Yep.
[SPEAKER_06] Thank you.
[SPEAKER_06] Ready?
[SPEAKER_06] All right.
[SPEAKER_05] Go find your person, please.
[SPEAKER_05] Go find your person.
[SPEAKER_05] I have rich news.
[SPEAKER_05] No.
[SPEAKER_05] Have sex.
[SPEAKER_00] Hey, here's insects.
[SPEAKER_05] What do you have?
[SPEAKER_05] Okay, so, for our next one, insects.
[SPEAKER_05] By yourself?
[SPEAKER_05] Josh, do you want me to stop this?
[SPEAKER_05] Let me get my notebook.
[SPEAKER_05] I'll do insects.
[SPEAKER_01] Do you want me to stop and take this outside?
[SPEAKER_02] Let's stop and just pause that one, and then we'll get another one that Jen will use outside.
[SPEAKER_06] Alright, I did that and those are my medics.
[SPEAKER_02] Can we get another?
[SPEAKER_06] Yes.
[SPEAKER_02] You have what you need?
[SPEAKER_02] I think so.
[SPEAKER_02] Lots of learning here.