[SPEAKER_03] And as you likely already know, salamanders are very sensitive organisms.
[SPEAKER_03] One of the reasons they're so sensitive is because they don't breathe through internal lungs in the same way that we mammals do.
[SPEAKER_03] They perform gas exchange through the medium of their skin.
[SPEAKER_03] Every part of the salamander is
[SPEAKER_03] opportunity, and so it's really important for us to make sure that we are not contaminating the salamander skin with any of the oils or contaminants on our skin, which could be hand sanitizer or soap or a little bit of salt from the snack you just ate.
[SPEAKER_03] We are going to instead use this
[SPEAKER_03] is going to be flipping up the rocks, and who's going to be holding the bag?
[SPEAKER_03] Of course, you can keep rotating those rolls as well.
[SPEAKER_03] So John, would you like to lift this black rock here?
[SPEAKER_01] Yeah.
[SPEAKER_04] If we are getting ready to lift the rock, we want to have our bag down low, ready to press against the ground, so if there's something under there, it doesn't run under the bag.
[SPEAKER_03] You ready?
[SPEAKER_05] Ready.
[SPEAKER_03] OK.
[SPEAKER_03] Oh, look.
[SPEAKER_03] Oh!
[SPEAKER_04] We actually got it.
[SPEAKER_03] orange china gecko um that's what's printed on the bottom of this guy underneath we're gonna put down our bag and then using something soft like a little leaf or something we can tickle the tail of our little friend and get it to run into our bags yes we got it seldom happens
[SPEAKER_03] that easily.
[SPEAKER_03] A lot of them are going to get away because they're small and they're fast and they're brown and you lose track of them.
[SPEAKER_03] If there had been nothing under our rock we would simply put the rock back gently in the same place that it was not like flinging it through the creek to hit someone else.
[SPEAKER_03] But because we have our salamander in the back
[SPEAKER_03] We're going to make sure that it's got a little bit of water.
[SPEAKER_03] I like to say maybe a fingernail worth of water in that bag with our salamander so it can stay moist and slimy for optimum gas exchange.
[SPEAKER_03] Zip this bag back up.
[SPEAKER_03] Don't have to worry about it because we've got oxygen from the bag as well as from the water.
[SPEAKER_03] And then we're going to bring this number one bag, salamander and water intact, back to our base.
[SPEAKER_03] zipped into its bag inside and exchange it for the number one cone, which is going to be placed in the same spot we found our salmon.
[SPEAKER_03] That way we're later able to collect data from that spot knowing that it was a spot that apparently is preferred by salmon.
[SPEAKER_03] Some rules about our salamander survey are that only one salamander can ever go in that bag.
[SPEAKER_03] So even if you find it next to three of its siblings, only one gets to go inside the bag.
[SPEAKER_03] The bag is only used for one salamander.
[SPEAKER_03] So if you have a salamander captured in your bag, you cannot dump them out and be like, no, I'm going for a bigger one.
[SPEAKER_03] Additionally, recommend that you not flip rocks that are bigger than your own head.
[SPEAKER_03] And just be a little bit careful of your feet as you're moving through the stream.
[SPEAKER_03] Sometimes we have a habit of jumping rock to rock, but since we know those rocks are also places salamanders prefer to be under,
[SPEAKER_03] We're going to establish some simple boundaries that will be from these fallen logs across the stream.
[SPEAKER_03] All the way up to here, the left fork of the stream begins in the bank and an approximate
[SPEAKER_03] minutes for this search if you have questions about your salamanders we might ask you to hold on to them but certainly if you have a salamander in the bag and you'd like to share it with
[SPEAKER_08] that when you're flipping rocks to flip them away from you and not towards you, why might that be a piece of advice?
[SPEAKER_08] Yeah, one when we set it back down and second, salamanders are not the only friends that live under rocks, so if you flip a rock and there is a snake or another critter that maybe you are less excited to see,
[SPEAKER_03] Yes.
[SPEAKER_03] Two people per bag.
[SPEAKER_03] That just means that we're not going to catch 18,000.
[SPEAKER_03] We're going to limit the number that we're going to catch.
[SPEAKER_03] Just a bag for now.
[SPEAKER_03] We won't give you the cone until you come back with your bag, but you need a bag and a partner for now.
[SPEAKER_06] Never caught.
[SPEAKER_06] Well, either one.
[SPEAKER_06] Either one of those things.
[SPEAKER_06] Just curious.
[SPEAKER_06] Not caught.
[SPEAKER_06] Yeah, I mean, this is a really cool thing.
[SPEAKER_06] We do it a lot, so for us it's like, oh, we're going to go get salamanders.
[SPEAKER_06] But it's exciting.
[SPEAKER_06] I guess it's not something you do every day, obviously, and it's just really fun.
[SPEAKER_06] Just take the time to just enjoy.
[SPEAKER_06] They're smaller than you think.
[SPEAKER_06] I mean, we might find adult salamanders that are that big.
[SPEAKER_03] Not all salamanders are aquatic, though, so we have terrestrial salamanders.
[SPEAKER_03] They are often found in places that stay really wet, so the high elevations where it's misty all the time is a great place for terrestrial salamanders.
[SPEAKER_03] All over the park is phenomenal compared to the rest of the world.
[SPEAKER_03] This is the salamander capital of the world.
[SPEAKER_03] Thirty-one.
[SPEAKER_03] Now we know.
[SPEAKER_03] Grab a buddy.
[SPEAKER_05] So if you're ready to be on camera I can be whatever.
[SPEAKER_05] Thank you.
[SPEAKER_05] Yeah.
[SPEAKER_05] I didn't see any better.
[SPEAKER_03] We don't get another bag.
[SPEAKER_05] I'm the only one.
[SPEAKER_05] Yeah.
[SPEAKER_03] On a day like today when it's just rain.
[SPEAKER_05] Who did not get their number?
[SPEAKER_05] That's not my salamander.
[SPEAKER_05] We got one with a little bit there.
[SPEAKER_03] I think I was three.
[SPEAKER_03] Oh my goodness, look how small he is.
[SPEAKER_05] Yeah.
[SPEAKER_02] Mars is number seven.
[SPEAKER_05] the one they just found.
[SPEAKER_05] I saw this.
[SPEAKER_03] We got one.
[SPEAKER_03] I'm just glad we found one.
[SPEAKER_03] That's a good idea.
[SPEAKER_03] Sell and face it with salamanders.
[SPEAKER_03] But when we do the snail survey, I'll be the only one that didn't find a snail.
[SPEAKER_03] And it's like, you feel like you're four years old.
[SPEAKER_03] And people are like, oh, you can buy a snail.
[SPEAKER_03] I want to do it myself.
[SPEAKER_05] You might need a tiny bit more water.
[SPEAKER_05] Yeah, he's cute.
[SPEAKER_05] Yeah, that looks great.
[SPEAKER_05] We're going to be looking at all these a little bit closer.
[SPEAKER_00] Sometimes I'm just like I'm talking like extra loud, but we're coming like around there.
[SPEAKER_03] Just make sure like alright, so we're coming over here.
[SPEAKER_05] Good.
[SPEAKER_07] Is that the seven?
[SPEAKER_07] That was ours.
[SPEAKER_07] Yeah, we tried to get some more in there.
[SPEAKER_07] He's in there.
[SPEAKER_03] Very well camouflaged.
[SPEAKER_03] Especially if you've got an itty bitty branch, recommend it.
And if you've got a really muddy bag, you can swap it out for, I think I caught eight, so eight is the word.
[SPEAKER_05] Yeah.
[SPEAKER_05] No.
[SPEAKER_06] Okay.
[SPEAKER_06] I see some additional details.
[SPEAKER_06] If you want to open the bag and look at him from above without the bag, that can really help see the clarity.
[SPEAKER_06] I'll try getting a little extra light on him.
[SPEAKER_06] So you can see a couple of details right there.
[SPEAKER_06] Like what's the main thing you see from on top?
[SPEAKER_06] Yeah.
[SPEAKER_06] Up between his front legs Yeah
[SPEAKER_06] Oh wow.
[SPEAKER_06] Look at that.
[SPEAKER_06] And if you look very closely behind his eyes, and you usually have to look from above, you may see some of the little gills, looks like little fingers coming from the side of his head.
[SPEAKER_06] And they look a little pinkish to me, a little reddish.
[SPEAKER_07] Almost like those, like, oxalotl-like.
[SPEAKER_06] Yeah, it is the same.
[SPEAKER_06] I caught you a new friend.
[SPEAKER_06] So yeah, see if you can do a little sketching of that, maybe even from a couple different perspectives.
[SPEAKER_02] I'm going to grab my paper.
[SPEAKER_02] I'll be right back.
[SPEAKER_02] Let me grab my paper.
[SPEAKER_06] I could clear that water up for you.
[SPEAKER_03] If you're stuck for things to notice, as you are preserving your salamander, there's a place out there.
[SPEAKER_03] Does it have spots?
[SPEAKER_03] How many?
[SPEAKER_03] What shade?
[SPEAKER_03] What do their eyes look like?
[SPEAKER_03] And try not to hold the salamander right on your palm, because we have such hot skin.
[SPEAKER_04] you're like he's
[SPEAKER_05] you
[SPEAKER_02] This is what I just got.
[SPEAKER_02] This one.
[SPEAKER_02] A tail and two pictures.
[SPEAKER_05] That's a good-looking salamander
[SPEAKER_06] semi, you know, translucent bellies.
[SPEAKER_06] You can see here those white, see that white line of spots right along the side?
[SPEAKER_06] Turn it, turn it, can you pick this out?
[SPEAKER_06] It's like a, if you look at it right on the side.
[SPEAKER_04] And if you're feeling like maybe you are, you stood up too fast.
[SPEAKER_04] If you are feeling like you are reaching the end of your drawing,
[SPEAKER_07] It's gonna be Inception.
[SPEAKER_04] There's Camception.
[SPEAKER_02] As they say, I'm the Fed.
[SPEAKER_08] This is gonna be weird.
[SPEAKER_07] I'm not used to doing one of these.
[SPEAKER_07] Camera show.
[SPEAKER_07] We're moving on.
[SPEAKER_02] Do you think he has black tits on his toes or that his toes are the same color as... They look... I think they look the same.
[SPEAKER_02] Same color as the rest of toe and foot.
[SPEAKER_02] I think so too.
[SPEAKER_02] Yeah.
[SPEAKER_02] Okay, go to seven.
[SPEAKER_02] Do you think he has a rounded snout?
[SPEAKER_02] Gills are like fingers rather than feathery plumes and are white or pale, not reddish.
[SPEAKER_02] Or...
[SPEAKER_02] You can have a snout with corners.
[SPEAKER_02] Gills like feathery coins.
[SPEAKER_07] I don't think it looks like corners.
[SPEAKER_02] Yeah.
[SPEAKER_02] Looks like rounded, right?
[SPEAKER_05] Yeah, I think so too.
[SPEAKER_02] Unidentified dusky salamander.
[SPEAKER_02] Let's look and see here.
[SPEAKER_07] There's also the, what's that, juvenile or what is it, larval?
[SPEAKER_07] That.
[SPEAKER_02] It does look more like that.
[SPEAKER_02] Cornered, yeah.
[SPEAKER_02] I'm glad they have a picture of round versus cornered.
[SPEAKER_02] Yeah, that's good.
[SPEAKER_02] Okay, so then.
[SPEAKER_02] usually shorter than 35 millimeters pairs of white spots down back now usually longer than 35 millimeters he was about that long gill's very red pores on face hard to see that i think again because it's small maybe he's a blue ridge two line salamander
[SPEAKER_07] Do you see I think they're down yeah, I think it's stripe the things below the stripes so maybe he's a Blue Ridge to live He could be whatever he wants
[SPEAKER_04] So one thing that we can look at is we have a different key for larva than adults.
[SPEAKER_04] Yes, we were looking down here.
[SPEAKER_04] And the gill shape is illustrated a little bit better on the back of whether we've got needles or feathers.
[SPEAKER_04] I don't think it's feathers.
[SPEAKER_04] That's really hard to see.
[SPEAKER_04] I think if we got a hand lens, it'd be more feather bows than punk rock spikes.
[SPEAKER_04] Right here, we're keying out a teeny tiny one.
[SPEAKER_04] He's right about 35.
[SPEAKER_02] Solid work.
[SPEAKER_03] Does he still have gills?
[SPEAKER_04] Yeah.
[SPEAKER_04] Very cool.
[SPEAKER_04] And they're like feather boa gills.
[SPEAKER_04] So the other one is much bigger.
[SPEAKER_04] So size is not necessarily a determinant for larva.
[SPEAKER_04] I have seen adults smaller than that.
[SPEAKER_02] So we're here at a pairs of white spots down back or gills very red horizontal face.
[SPEAKER_04] There you go.
[SPEAKER_02] Crushing it.
[SPEAKER_03] Then you as your buddy may say farewell to your salamander.
[SPEAKER_03] Now to release your salamander you're going to take it back to it.
[SPEAKER_03] I want to make sure you hear this first even if you're not ready.
[SPEAKER_03] Bless you.
[SPEAKER_03] And I'm going to take my salamander back.
I'm going to kneel down by the cone.
[SPEAKER_05] And I'm going to gently take my first bag and take my second.
[SPEAKER_03] I am not going to take up the rock paper and replace the salamander and the rock back on top.
[SPEAKER_03] Fair enough.
[SPEAKER_03] Then you can double check that bag before you bring that back.
[SPEAKER_03] You're going to leave the cone in place, so don't put the bag in place.
[SPEAKER_03] Keep the cone in place.
[SPEAKER_03] And so that's it.
[SPEAKER_05] You ready?