[SPEAKER_06] some of you can tell they kind of went through it because some of them will be very they really want an outlet to talk about some of the things that are important to them
[SPEAKER_06] So yeah.
[SPEAKER_01] So what Dana doing though, this art base data?
[SPEAKER_06] And I think that'd be really good, because like art gardens look very different.
[SPEAKER_06] Mine is just a cloud of dirt right now with a sign.
[SPEAKER_06] Good for now.
[SPEAKER_00] So how would y'all, if you guys don't want to make that a visual, would we be creating something that visualizes each of the gardens, or would it be something there?
[SPEAKER_01] I know y'all have some neighbors.
[SPEAKER_01] So I would say the first step would be to think on what kind of day do you want to show.
[SPEAKER_05] What would be your guiding question, I guess?
[SPEAKER_05] Whose garden is going to make the most fruit?
[SPEAKER_05] Or whose garden is going to attract the most pollinators?
[SPEAKER_05] Or whose garden is going to be the most weeding, and whose garden is going to sound like that?
[SPEAKER_03] We're going to bring it back together real quick.
[SPEAKER_03] I'm going to ask you all just to kind of go around in a circle, each group, kind of just state a couple of things.
[SPEAKER_03] And if the answer is I don't know to these questions, totally fine.
[SPEAKER_03] I'm going to ask actually one.
[SPEAKER_03] What is the thing that you are excited about?
[SPEAKER_03] What is the thing that you're doing?
[SPEAKER_03] If it's a unit, what are your quick, maybe 15-second plans for that unit that you've all decided on as a group?
[SPEAKER_04] Gosh, you like these microphones.
[SPEAKER_03] I'm gonna start off with Catherine's group over here, and then we'll work our way this way.
[SPEAKER_01] All right, we got a pretty good team here.
[SPEAKER_01] There's four of us because that's just how it worked out.
[SPEAKER_01] Sorry if you only got three.
[SPEAKER_01] So there's four of us.
[SPEAKER_01] We're gonna be throughout AP Environmental Science and Environmental Systems and Societies.
[SPEAKER_01] We all talk about albedo a lot and reflectivity and climate change and all the cycles and positive feedback and negative feedback and balancing.
[SPEAKER_01] Unbalancing and so they have a lab that they have done before and now we're ramping it up a little bit and we've also talked about Not yet, but in the future.
[SPEAKER_01] Hopefully we have a common database where we're basically
[SPEAKER_01] Taking temperatures that we can compare from like year to year, because we're going to have coordinates of the location and all that we can compare from year to year.
[SPEAKER_01] And we can also compare three different schools.
[SPEAKER_01] So, Farragut versus Bearden versus West, where you can look at the Google Maps and like see the
[SPEAKER_01] Forestry and you can see where there are more trees.
[SPEAKER_01] And also we just planted like 14 trees at West So we're talking about like over time taking those temperature recordings at the same place like next to the trees as they like develop to and see if we can see any Changes on that.
[SPEAKER_01] Is that everything that good?
[SPEAKER_06] Yeah, so we talked about a lot of different things
[SPEAKER_06] We both have some space to be kind of what we want.
[SPEAKER_06] So Vincent and I are thinking about doing something possibly with TV production, but ending with our students doing some art-based data visuals of art.
[SPEAKER_05] So we talked about some standards and two of them that seemed to lend towards place-based data with taxonomy.
[SPEAKER_05] So just like at least going outdoors and looking at domains and kingdoms, identifying things through that, using the naturalist.
[SPEAKER_05] And then creating models using the carbon cycle for synthesis.
[SPEAKER_05] observations, potentially even throwing in a CO2 sensor, gathering data with that, maybe seeing changes over time, maybe looking at in the classroom, difference between basement timeout versus home, maybe even over time looking at our location versus the Episcopal School location.
[SPEAKER_05] Maybe more next year than this year.
[SPEAKER_03] I love these multi-place data sets ideas.
[SPEAKER_00] That's very David's group.
[SPEAKER_00] So David and I teach AP slash IV bio, and I teach bio one.
[SPEAKER_00] So we're looking at a way to incorporate both of those, especially with new bio one things.
[SPEAKER_00] And so Michelle brought up some of the stuff that our BSCS doesn't cover, including
[SPEAKER_00] teach and so we were talking about comparing behavior of termites which are an insect versus behavior or lack thereof of roly-polys which are an arthropods and how communication allows termites and communal insects like that to have a selective or
[SPEAKER_00] a natural selection advantage over individuals like roly-polies and how that communication and signaling can help them find resources more quickly versus the lack of communication in something like a roly-poly.
[SPEAKER_00] That sounds awesome.
[SPEAKER_00] Not exactly place, but... It sounds awesome.
[SPEAKER_01] They're both native.
[SPEAKER_01] You can play with roly-polies.
[SPEAKER_01] You can go out and get them.
[SPEAKER_01] Yes, very true.
[SPEAKER_04] We all teach bio one and we talked about sort of sticking in the ecology world and looking at the changes potentially in the environment affecting biodiversity and we talked about maybe doing soil quality or water quality measurements and again
[SPEAKER_03] All right, before I pass it over to Josh, just to schedule-wise, we're going to meet at 3.30 at the Friendship Circle to do some salamander explorations.
[SPEAKER_02] I have one, two, three, four quick notes.
[SPEAKER_02] First, hearing about your curriculum, what fits, what doesn't, was great.
[SPEAKER_02] And we want to keep foregrounding that.
[SPEAKER_02] that can't connect to what you do.
[SPEAKER_02] So keep sharing about your curriculum, your context.
[SPEAKER_02] That's really valuable.
[SPEAKER_02] Related, I know many of you teach biology in Knox County now have this new curriculum, which is very prescribed.
[SPEAKER_02] It looks good.
[SPEAKER_02] It's very prescribed.
[SPEAKER_02] And so we had some interesting conversations or groups about how to work within that constraint.
[SPEAKER_02] I think in terms of the curriculum,
[SPEAKER_02] It's really good, but there's still room to do more with data.
[SPEAKER_02] That's partially a function of where the science education field is.
[SPEAKER_02] Data, despite being so central to science, just as a very simple statement, it's kind of been peripheral science education, even for upper level high school science.
[SPEAKER_02] A lot of times the data sets are pretty cookie cutter.
[SPEAKER_02] The investigations with data are pretty broke compared
[SPEAKER_02] So we think there's still room to push.
[SPEAKER_02] And in some ways, kind of leave the field humbly in terms of what's showing what's possible.
[SPEAKER_02] So that's the first note of our curriculum.
[SPEAKER_02] Second is, there were some cool conversations about why we use data.
[SPEAKER_02] And that's something we really like to study and learn more about.
[SPEAKER_02] What kinds of questions are worth asking with data?
[SPEAKER_02] If we already know the answer, maybe we don't need to collect data.
[SPEAKER_02] Just look it up.
[SPEAKER_02] But we might not know about local specifics.
[SPEAKER_02] We might not know about the quality of the soil at our school.
[SPEAKER_02] There literally might be no measurements on it.
[SPEAKER_02] GPT can't tell us.
[SPEAKER_02] It could guess.
[SPEAKER_02] But your students could probably generate a better answer.
[SPEAKER_02] So try to figure out kind of where the value add is with data.
[SPEAKER_02] Some cool conversations around that.
[SPEAKER_02] Sort of related, we want to learn from a variety of different cases.
[SPEAKER_02] Like trying stuff out and failing is very valuable, actually.
[SPEAKER_02] That's part of the value of our research project is we can afford to kind of try
[SPEAKER_02] Lastly, just a few notes on logistics.
[SPEAKER_02] We hope you're involved for more than one year, actually.
[SPEAKER_02] We didn't really say that yet, but we have a solid two years of funding.
[SPEAKER_02] And actually, a year after that, that's more wrap up.
[SPEAKER_02] But we have solid two years of funding for participating teachers, for teacher leaders.
[SPEAKER_02] And so that's to say, if you want to start small this year, try something minimal, viable, lesson.
[SPEAKER_02] And use that as a chance to maybe plan for more next year.
[SPEAKER_02] Small thing that's sort of, it's under my logistics heading, but it's a little different.
[SPEAKER_02] There were some discussions about student collected data, which sometimes is called first-hand data, and data that's provided to students, second-hand data.
[SPEAKER_02] One's not better than the other.
[SPEAKER_02] There's awesome secondary data sets, but there's also value in students collecting data, like in these examples we talked about, where there might not be data on the creep by your school.
[SPEAKER_02] And so I just want to encourage you all to think about both, first and second hand data.
[SPEAKER_02] Again, one's not better than the other.
[SPEAKER_02] You might think about sequencing them or trying one in a case where you'd use the other first things and see if there's different benefits to kids learning.
[SPEAKER_02] Lastly, my last note is we like different and weird stuff.
[SPEAKER_02] The only anchor, back to the very first thing we shared, is there's these four pillars of the project we want to try to encourage you to touch on.
[SPEAKER_02] The data investigation process, so thinking about ways kids can engage not just in one part of the data cycle, not just looking at a graph or creating a graph, but also being able to ask questions, maybe even clean data, maybe
[SPEAKER_02] Something around statistical analysis even, maybe, where a statistic can be as simple as a mean.
[SPEAKER_02] That's a very powerful statistic that actually can be super useful.
[SPEAKER_02] So the data investigation cycle, place-based learning is the second.
[SPEAKER_02] The third is this thing we haven't talked about as much, but thinking about data not in terms of yes, no answers, but how confident we can be about different ideas we have and hypotheses.
[SPEAKER_02] And then lastly, this ambitious science teaching approach.
[SPEAKER_02] So those are four big things.
[SPEAKER_02] Those are each huge.
[SPEAKER_02] But trying to think about how you can incorporate aspects of these, knowing that the third and the fourth, we haven't really began to talk about yet.
[SPEAKER_02] That's all.
[SPEAKER_02] So I really enjoyed hearing your conversations, and looking forward to continuing.
[SPEAKER_02] Yeah, really cool projects.
[SPEAKER_03] They all sound really exciting.
[SPEAKER_03] And we're just getting started.
[SPEAKER_03] Again, friendship circle at 3.30.
[SPEAKER_02] Five minutes.
[SPEAKER_02] We didn't get tested out earlier, so I'm going to leave them right here.
[SPEAKER_05] If you can't pick up a schedule, you'll know what the heck is going on.
[SPEAKER_03] Let's say 3.35, and I'll warn everyone.
[SPEAKER_01] I don't know what that means
[SPEAKER_01] Yeah, bring your notebook.
[SPEAKER_05] Oh, and something to write, I guess, and make sure you're like, how can they join?