Okay.
It wasn't on.
Mine did the same thing.
So what is yours doing?
Because his might not have as much battery.
No, his was on.
The screen will go out.
Welcome back y'all to this other side of the valley.
The West Farm Trail yesterday we had the chance to explore towards the cemetery.
We're going to end at the cemetery today, but we'll do a little loop on our hike.
and during our little hike we are going to have the chance to put on our learner hat one more time and practice a strategy and activity that we love here that also we've heard from a lot of educators is really applicable across grade levels and content areas and we've heard lots of creative ways that this is being used.
It's an activity called beach to teach to
And this morning I was really thinking about Eat, Shoe, Teach, Shoe when John read the quote at breakfast by Rachel Carson where she talks about how knowing is not half as important as loving.
And Eat, Shoe, Teach, Shoe gives us the space to really love and connect with this place or the place where you find yourself in.
and it gives you that chance to connect and maybe in a little bit new or different way.
Yesterday we connected with salamanders and salamanders are so cute and they have the littlest, tidiest toes and sometimes little black toe paths and like it's like love at first sight with a salamander.
But when you're in the woods or you're in your neighborhood or you're in a park we might not connect with everything as quickly or as deeply as the face or the toes of a salamander.
but East Shoe Teeshoe gives us a lens to start to think about that connection, to see our place in maybe a little bit different way.
And oftentimes when we are doing science, we think about the so what.
We're just a welcome home committee, that's why.
She says she's a retired teacher.
I don't think when I during the time I was here.
How's the pension?
3rd, 4th, 7th.
All of the above.
Mostly science.
Science, STEM.
There is no pension.
More teachers!
Yes.
So oftentimes this week we are really focused on data collection, thinking about this probabilistic thinking and revising our thinking, collecting more data, adding to the story.
And oftentimes we wait till the end of that process to think about the so what behind it.
So what, why are we even studying this?
But making these connections helps us put that so what at the beginning to help frame and connect us to the work throughout the process instead of just at the end.
So here's how each two teach to is going to work.
In just a minute we will all together as a group hike up to that junction where yesterday we veered off to the right up to the cemetery.
The whole group is going to stay put at that spot and I as a lonesome hiker is going to head up the trail for a little bit.
And as I am hiking, I'm going to be looking for something cool.
It could be a species, it could be a medicinal plant, it could be connecting with the sounds around us, it could be artistic.
Something that stands out to me in the trail in that space.
And after about two-ish minutes, Grayson is going to send the first two people up the trail.
And those first partners, their job is to hike until you find me.
When you find me, I am going to teach you about whatever thing I stopped to look at or connect with, and then that becomes your station.
So then you and your partners stay put there, and you will then teach the subsequent partners whatever that thing was as they come through.
You are all teachers, so whatever I teach you is one way to say it, but you might have a way to add to it, to give it a little flair, add a little creativity.
So the way that you deliver and share that thing is up to you and your partner.
after did you want to say okay no i'm modeling the sleeves okay so after about two more minutes Grayson will send the next pair that pair will hike up the trail until they find the first pair they will stop at that first pair and learn whatever the fact is from that pair that first pair will stay put the second pair keeps hiking until they find it
And then I will teach them something at that spot.
That will become their station.
They make it their own.
Think about how they want to share it.
They stay put.
I keep hiking.
Two minutes later, Grayson sends the third pair.
That third pair stops at the first pair and learns.
Stops at the second pair and learns.
Keeps hiking until they find me.
I will teach them something.
This might be a really bad game of telephone.
Yeah.
So we are all unzipped along the trail.
Grayson is going to be last.
So once everybody has their station, she will come to you and you can teach her your thing.
When you see Grayson, you know that John is done.
after you teach and then she's going to kind of stay put and you will make your way for the stations ahead of you you are then the participant she will then come to the next station they will teach her that they will keep walking the next they will keep walking until we all zip back up into one group at the end where another junction What questions do we have about each student?
If it doesn't make sense, yeah, that's fine.
It'll be very clear what you need to do one step at a time.
It feels like a gallery wall.
Similar to a gallery wall?
Yep.
All right.
So as I said in my instructions, and as the name implies, you do need a partner for this activity.
So if you'll take a moment, find one other person to work with.
And if we are odd, we are all odds.
But if we are unodd, then we could have a one group.
So give your partner a high five when you've got them.
That was awkward.
Everybody is partnered?
It was his camera.
All right, I'm going to start making my way very soon.
Yeah, you're blending.
Everybody's blending in with their shirts.
It's me!
Are we starting up there?
They're all going at the same time.
If we shared this with our school group, then we got it all wrong.
It's like as we went along, the person at the station would tell us that all of the people knew the next one.
Then we'd pick that person and they'd tell us about it.
And we like walked in the last circle.
I'm happy right now.
Without the sleeves.
I decided to layer this so I can wear the shirt.
Now I've got a dress under it and I don't know how long that'll last.
Sure might come off.
Have you seen Mr. Moss?
It's got a very dramatic... It's like it needs the shape.
Sporophytes or something.
Oh wow!
It's so... Yeah, it looks unusual.
It looks like it's just lifting.
Well, it's, yeah, I mean, it's a little bit of, see, yeah, a little bit of foliage growing out of it.
I mean, these little structures are not lifted so much as eroded.
You know, the little stone kind of protected that as the rain maybe was hitting it.
And here, I mean, probably this moss is keeping it from
We should do okay Grayson you have you got something they're gonna do here We're just waiting.
I don't think anybody should I think everybody should try to find a caterpillar.
I
All right, first buddy pair may launch.
all right trio all right for those of us who are waiting um bonus points for the first person to find a caterpillar there's also a lot of poison ivy around us so caterpillar hunt with care
No, I don't know what it's like.
You get tokens, I'm in.
Grace behaviorist, all the way.
I didn't know that.
I'm hoping I will have behaviorist.
No, I don't think so.
Oh, I'm so sorry.
I got hired to do it because I had worked in school gardens and they were like so when have you
When have you been in the classroom before?
And I was like, oh, you know, just like, I didn't even grow up in a public school.
Like our hall pass is real.
I didn't have much leeway to do.
I just turn on the back shirts and sit and wait for 25 minutes.
That was something.
This job is always a little bit different.
Let me take a picture.
Did you see this one?
See this one over here?
This one on the other side of that log.
Should get the shelf mushrooms.
Yeah, I feel like those are common though.
Yeah.
More common than that for sure.
What about the little bitty ones there?
Yeah, there's like those and then those.
It looks like those is what those turn into.
I don't see these.
So one's a bitty?
Yeah, I think those are little and those are bigger.
That starts looking like this.
Yeah, I don't know but those don't have see those almost start as like regular mushroom heads Whereas that one doesn't seem like the start of the head You know See
Oh, my gosh.
I'm almost buzzing in here.
Mm-hmm.
All right, guys, group, onwards.
All right.
All right, got it.
I kind of remember.
No, I remember when I was in college.
I spent my classes all the time.
I didn't even have some hair.
I'm just an educator.
It's like, oh, I'm so glad I've seen that.
Yeah.
Thank you.
And then giving them
because they're not learning nearly as much socially as they please have to do.
And really, yeah, it's still, I mean, it's been long.
Right, I think it just popped out.
I'm done.
We came back off that road.
We went out and just came pulling off railroad tracks.
Really easy.
And there's a part in the book where he talks about like, um, it's become really socially acceptable if you're done talking to somebody you just gave your phone to and that's when he signals you and he doesn't want to talk to them anymore.
And I feel like the Gen Z stare is a version of that where it's like, my son does it all the time, he's 14, and I'm talking to him and he's just looking at me and I'm like, you need to say like, okay, or I hear you, or can you clarify, like, where can I be?
But he'll just get up and walk away.
Following me.
It's following me.
It sure is.
Oh my gosh.
How am I going to get ahold of my child?
They're not supposed to be on it anyway.
They're not supposed to be on it.
We're moving to the yonder couches this year.
We have phone jails.
We have really good principals also.
There's not a principal in our building that you could call and be like, this kid's mom keeps calling him.
And they wouldn't come in and be like, phone jail.
They have a box and it's got a padlock.
Get in phone jail.
Your mom can come get it later.
If my mom texted me in school, it would have said, I hope you get detention finished.
It better be an emergency.
Oh, hey, I'm picking you up later.
I love you.
Like you don't need to check right now.
It's the, and then it ties into just the anxiety around it.
But it's like, there's a notification, I saw this, I gotta check it.
I need to check it.
I need to look at it.
I need to do this.
It's so wild being here where I don't get most of the, like, culture of TikTok and stuff.
And at my house, I have no internet.
That'd probably be good.
having one of the cameras towards the end and Vincent's already gone so you'll have one towards the middle.
Was it intentional to have it upside down?
That's what he said.
He said otherwise it kind of starts to fall over.
So hopefully when it goes to play the video there's the rotate button.
It's going to be all kinds of awkward.
He was looking at it last night.
Hey Josh, what's up?
Kim here, coming to you from the trail.
Reporting from Project Credible.
Science teachers want to know, what do you think of pineapple on pizza?
I will eat one piece of it, but other than that, no.
I'm a vegetable on pizza person, not a fruit on pizza person.
Okay, okay.
All right.
Hoping for a different perspective here.
I'm all about charcuterie boards, so bring it on.
Yeah, bring it on?
Yeah, bring it on.
So, the question is, what do you at home think?
Pineapple on pizza.
Like and subscribe.
Right.
Just tap that subscribe button right down there, y'all.
Tap a little like, you know, if you like what you see.
Or if you don't like what you see.
If you want to see more data science education, like and subscribe, yo.
Yo.
Hey bro, we want to see you.
We do need a teacher channel.
Legit.
Today in the life.
Do you need to go to the bathroom?
And you're like, no, I said skivity.
I said, skid marks in your pants?
I'm like, no, you don't go to the bathroom and take care of that.
And nobody, they stopped with that in my class.
It took about three or four people to do that.
And I was like, oh, that's embarrassing for you.
I told you, you out weird.
You gotta be the alpha weird.
And I feel like there's such value for them seeing an adult be goofy and embarrassing and like, yep, listen, the world kept turning.
Someday you'll accidentally embarrass yourself and yeah, things won't just stop.
Oh, when they're sagging, when they're sagging, you tell them all, unless you're a man pant.
I've never heard that.
If I stay at my home, whatever I want to, those are hand pants.
I used to frequently, if the boys are wrestling, it's just like, can we just stop touching each other?
Any goat works, boys, boys, boys, girls, boys, boys, girls.
I'll tell them to go in the hall.
I'm like, go touch yourselves in the hall, please.
So we have it on camera.
I used to, I used to, I would get up and be like, I don't mean to alarm you, but your butt has ticked off your pants.
And they're running off.
And it's, they're so confused, they're like, ooh!
All right, next.
Joey?
Okay.
Is that a nest?
Oh, it sure looks like one.
My eyes are to see them.
I can't quite tell the definition that it looks like.
It looks like, yeah, a stick bundle rather than, um, like a burl or something.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
That's what I was thinking.
Okay, I'm going to travel now.
You, yeah, brought the wrong person to tell you who might live in a nest like that.
Blair.
Um.
Oh, yeah.
Okay, great.
I'm glad that you were able to follow me.
My eyes are not what they used to be.
It looks more leafy than sticky.
Is it?
From this angle but the sun's coming in so bright.
Yeah, yeah.
From here it looks more leafy than sticky.
I get called on to explain burrows in trees pretty, pretty often.
Cool.
And I've found that I tell kids oh it's like you know it's like a tree wart.
You know it's like a benign tree tumor and it's just got curly grain in there but it's
like the DNA went wonky and told it to grow a bubble.
Yeah.
Can that be insect-induced too?
Certainly the galls can, but like the really big burrows in the trees tend to be solid rather than hollow.
Okay.
And the burrows are tree tissue, like cancerous tissue, right?
Essentially, in the sense that it's uncontrolled growth.
I had no idea what the difference was.
Warts don't have to be viral, but sometimes they are.
They are still benign overgrowth is what warts are.
I think I was using those interchangeably, not thinking about the reason for the distinction.
The root of the cause.
Yeah.
And sometimes a burl can result from damage to the tree and foreign DNA getting in.
That kind of tricks it into overgrowth.
Because I was thinking a lot of it was like
scar mm-hmm it can start out as a scar okay all right y'all can head on all right oh those are cute see I would have stopped here and not even made it 30 seconds those are really pretty
Like a cypress Like a brown cypress or a brown cedar?
Maybe You do have that flat scaly texture
I guess it would be cypress because they are flat.
These are, these, no, these are the, are these the, yeah, it's the one with two.
Do you remember the
Not persimmon.
I swear it starts with a P though.
But you can't eat them.
It's got two eyeballs.
Oh, you see that?
I don't remember what they're called.
I learned it.
I learned it a year ago.
Yeah, it's a distinctive feature.
It means it's edible.
Just with this particular plant, not when like general.
But I don't think I have service to do anything with it.
Well, I can take the picture then go back and lens it later.
I can't remember what it's called.
But yeah, it is something edible.
So the two means you... Yeah, just hold on to it though because I want to double check because if I don't... I'm pretty sure... Hold on.
You see the two eyeballs?
The lens is there.
Right there.
I was holding it to the screen.
See, that supposedly means it's edible.
Alicia's going to try it.
Look, I have two berries.
It's just Grayson.
Okay, guys.
You already were looking at some stuff over there.
Yep.
That's the same stuff.
Same stuff.
Oh, perfect.
So everyone has an example of it.
Anything unique about it?
You can eat it.
Yes.
Do you already know?
Do you know about it?
Yep.
You can eat it.
Okay.
No, no, no.
Not that one.
How many seeds are you finding inside?
You just ate two, right?
How many seeds you got?
I don't know.
I think I chewed them up.
Okay.
You can kind of squeeze it if you want and you can kind of feel it pop.
But was there anything you noticed at the top?
Two eyeballs.
Two?
Okay.
So it's a berry.
What normally are in berries or on the sides of it?
Seeds.
Seeds?
Okay.
And so there is two holes.
So how many seeds do we presume is inside?
Two.
Two?
Two or four.
Yeah.
So obviously this is the reproductive part.
What makes you think about like how it was made?
How many individuals were involved for the flowering part?
it has to be sexual reproduction to have a seed and a fruit.
And each of those, like you squished it, but there was those two little holes on there, right?
So you've got the two little holes, you've got the two little seeds.
What did those holes hold before?
Like before the fruit formed?
Flowers.
Yeah, the flowers.
So two flowers, right?
So and it
OK, she's right there.
I think we'll be OK.
But so there's two flowers that was made.
And then we mentioned the leaves and I think we covered everything.
So do you guys want to know the name yet?
Yep.
Partridge berry.
There it is.
It started with a P. It did start with a P. And then, yeah, so the ground cover, see how all the leaves are just twos and twos and twos and then two flowers, two seeds.
This one has four seeds.
Oh, sometimes fours.
Yeah.
If it's an even number.
You could have doubles.
Yep.
I got twins.
Okay guys, thank you so much.
Thank you.
It doesn't taste like much, but you can eat it.
There's more.
See, this is where I messed up with my students.
Once we got to there, the last one, when they told their story, we all missed one.
Yeah, so by the end, the whole class met up at the end.
Where did you take your shoes?
This on your campus?
Here?
No, this is a trip to chain off with the kids.
Yeah, we bring a group every year.
Um, we do a little bit of co-teaching.
Touch it.
Thou shalt not pass.
But you can touch it.
We are, it is indeed a sensory station.
Touch my knees.
Touch it.
All of you.
You must participate.
You must touch and believe.
Tell me about your sensory leaf experience.
That's very big.
And soft.
Underneath.
The top is more of a silky smooth, the bottom is more of a... Furry-ish?
It's got texture.
I don't know if I'd call it fuzzy or furry like a lamb's ear, but it's got texture.