In terms of data, firsthand data, how would you use those?
Well, like we said, the place is where you are, right?
So place-based data or place-based lessons.
Those are things we can find out.
Ooh.
using the language of probability.
I was just gonna ask what is Spell Bayesian you keep using that word over and over and over.
What is it like B IZ or B?
Okay.
Thank you.
I totally had that spelled wrong.
Yeah, I had no idea the word you were using.
Oh, it's so many pages.
Do I have to put my name in?
It's so many pages, bro.
All included in her communication.
Thank you.
Well, the sticky note brainstorming thing we did out in the friendship circle and then dividing up, I mean, that was all included, heard in communication.
And then rearranging the sticky notes and all that good stuff.
for themselves but also for me and we hang them on the board and we revisit them regularly and it's a lot easier for me to say like you said this is how you wanted to
you're still talking about the interconnectedness between.
species here, right?
Yes, biodiversity is necessary.
And there's lots of places where we have people go out and we're paying to remove honeysuckle, or we are going out volunteering to remove honeysuckle, right?
With our IB science juniors, we are working together with IAMS.
And IAMS is focusing on bird scats.
Is it really worth the time to remove all these invasives?
Is it helping the birds?
Is it hurting the birds?
What kind of biodiversity
They all die.
those to whatever standards you'd like if you want to use this exact same activity.
be like, all right, who knows what this word means?
Who knows what this word means, right?
Because that's the objective.
So then last year, with the mindset of Project Credible, I started to put a little bit more of this on the students.
So more of them dissecting the objective and them modeling what they think this is going to look like.
Thank you.
Now go ahead and go to the second part.
Join your shoulder partner or group mates and see if you came up with similar definitions.
So just talk about what you wrote down.
If you knew one that they didn't, then go ahead and talk to them about that.
random, no plan pattern, systemic, no plan pattern.
right looking for the beginning letter
So go ahead and flip the paper, but try not to look at the adjoining page.
I know that's silly.
So just try and flip it and look at this one right here, where it says third, fourth, fifth.
Don't look at the adjoining page.
It's just there for the next step.
So now third, fourth, fifth.
And once again, we're doing this with our students.
Yeah.
to this exact same coordinate and look at this exact same spot.
They could assess the biodiversity year after year and compare that to other places, right?
up a little bit at the moment.
So we're going to change it up just a little bit when we get outside, and we're actually going to decide what species we see the most of, and then we're going to classify those as A through B. So we all have like five species that are common, and then we're going to have
Once again, this is just stuff I show my students on Canvas.
at your objective again.
So we are going to figure out, evaluate population abundance of non-modal species.
What does that mean?
Non-movie.
We are going to estimate.
Is it going to be perfect?
Heck no.
We're going to do random, systematic, or transect.
What do y'all think if we're using hula hoop?
and see where it lands.
So when I first started doing this, it was in January.
We were outside, and we were just assessing the biodiversity of what's in the grass, really.
And now we have a native garden, so we can use it a little bit more for that and stuff.
So yeah.
So you need your journal.
I think what we're going to do now is I left the hula hoops outside.
We're not using quadrants.
Grab a partner, grab a hula hoop, and I'll give you further instructions.
We're going to kind of go wear moth and batlets.
And bear poop.
Close your eyes.