[SPEAKER_01] It's talked over.
[SPEAKER_01] Ignored.
[SPEAKER_01] You know, maybe somebody made assumptions about you and it was hurtful.
[SPEAKER_01] So I want to revisit this because we have already had some of this get stepped on a little bit.
[SPEAKER_01] And already in our collaborative group of well-meaning, really good people, there's already been a little bit of hurt feelings just in interaction.
[SPEAKER_01] So I don't really have an idea of who this is, but what I love, and I say this to my staff, it's the norms are great, and almost everybody can come up with a good set of norms.
[SPEAKER_01] The living within those norms is tricky.
[SPEAKER_01] Because oftentimes, and one of our usual norms is like,
[SPEAKER_01] take ownership over the impacts that you have.
[SPEAKER_01] And usually everyone's like, of course I do that.
[SPEAKER_01] But you don't always know the impacts that you have.
[SPEAKER_01] And sometimes you can hurt somebody's feelings, never know that you did.
[SPEAKER_01] Because you certainly didn't intend to, but something you said or a way that you said it caught somebody wrong.
[SPEAKER_01] And in those moments, you'd never know.
[SPEAKER_01] Like the person would be hurt, the person who did it would never know, and we'd all go on, and the system remains the same.
[SPEAKER_01] But in our situation, and what I like about our staff, what I like about this group already is sharing that.
[SPEAKER_01] Sharing that sense that I got my feelings.
[SPEAKER_01] this happened and I just wanted to bring it up.
[SPEAKER_01] So it came to me.
[SPEAKER_01] So I just want us to know, this stuff is happening.
[SPEAKER_01] And we don't mean it and we don't intend it typically.
[SPEAKER_01] So I would call us just to think about, and really I would go back to the thing we had written down in here a number of times, the idea of affirming gestures, heard included, collaborative.
[SPEAKER_01] I know that kind and positive is written on here.
[SPEAKER_01] Really focus on how we respond to things, how we talk about things, language that we use.
[SPEAKER_01] And if you end up on the wrong side of that, you're like, shoot.
[SPEAKER_01] I didn't sit very well with me.
[SPEAKER_01] Tell somebody.
[SPEAKER_01] Don't sit there.
[SPEAKER_01] Don't suffer.
[SPEAKER_01] Don't think, oh, it's just because of this or that, or they didn't mean it, so I'm just not going to say anything.
[SPEAKER_01] If you had that moment, just say it.
[SPEAKER_01] I mean, this is probably the most friendly group of people you're going to work with.
[SPEAKER_01] I mean, these are people that really want to do the best by everybody.
[SPEAKER_01] So this is how we learn.
[SPEAKER_01] And this is what happens in classrooms.
[SPEAKER_01] This is what happens in every group.
[SPEAKER_01] We learn by going like, oh, shoot, I did not realize it.
[SPEAKER_01] So I do this now because we're going to be working together all afternoon, all evening, tomorrow, and then hopefully later on after we leave here.
[SPEAKER_01] And I want everybody to feel good about ourselves.
[SPEAKER_01] This is not John's calling somebody out.
[SPEAKER_01] He's just recognizing that somewhere along the line, we didn't quite live up to our best selves.
[SPEAKER_01] And so just rethink, reconsider, think, how am I responding?
[SPEAKER_01] I think we're all doing very, very well.
[SPEAKER_01] But it may be, I mean we may spend a little more time even in the next couple days just unpacking like what does this look like?
[SPEAKER_01] What does this look like when it doesn't happen?
[SPEAKER_01] Have you ever had it happen that you got something hurt and the person didn't know?
[SPEAKER_01] They didn't know?
[SPEAKER_01] Were you able to bring it up?
[SPEAKER_01] Was there enough safety there to bring something up?
[SPEAKER_01] Like that's tricky.
[SPEAKER_01] I'm just glad to know that this is that kind of place we can do it.
[SPEAKER_01] So these are sitting over there.
[SPEAKER_01] We wrote them down.
[SPEAKER_01] Yeah, I just wanted to bring that up while we're, I think, all together and have a chance just to say, OK, all of us are fallible.
[SPEAKER_01] All of us have blind spots.
[SPEAKER_01] Let's just take some time and appreciate it.
[SPEAKER_01] So thank you for your time.
[SPEAKER_01] Thanks for the flexibility, because this is the way that things happen.
[SPEAKER_01] We have rain, and we usually just run out in the rain with our pachos on and do our thing.
[SPEAKER_01] We have rain and thunder and lightning.
[SPEAKER_01] Let's just take it.
[SPEAKER_01] We can flex things around.
[SPEAKER_01] Cody is flexible.
[SPEAKER_01] We're flexible.
[SPEAKER_01] Salamanders love the rain, so they're going to be even happier by the time we get out there in a little bit.
[SPEAKER_01] We'll continue on with the latter part of the afternoon now, and then we'll hit the salamanders.
[SPEAKER_01] What time do you think that will end up being?
[SPEAKER_01] Cody, it's 2.20 right now.
[SPEAKER_00] We actually, you let us know when the best time for you to start would be, and we'll figure that out.
[SPEAKER_00] So I think that we can take 30 minutes to an hour.
[SPEAKER_00] I'm just going to give them a lot of time to kind of work and think and reflect.
[SPEAKER_01] Yeah, so it's 2.20.
[SPEAKER_01] So if we could be done with this and have a little break before, be ready to start on salamanders around 3.30.
[SPEAKER_01] That'd be an hour and 10 from now.
[SPEAKER_01] Everybody's going to be ready to get up.
[SPEAKER_01] Thank you, John.
[SPEAKER_01] We'll take another look at the weather then, and we'll see what we need.
[SPEAKER_02] Can I ask you a really quick question?
[SPEAKER_02] I mean, sorry, I'm getting a vaccine.
[SPEAKER_02] Okay, so like in Google Sheets, there's an activity I always do when we're doing introduction to population, J-curve, boom bust, all that, and the students have to select, do you want it to be a line graph, a bar graph, pie chart?
[SPEAKER_02] This one is auto doing it, so if I was comparing data and normally it would show up as a bar graph, does it auto bar graph it versus changes over time, doing a line graph?
[SPEAKER_00] I can.
[SPEAKER_00] You can make it.
[SPEAKER_00] You can switch between them pretty quickly and easily and I'll show you how to do that when we have some time.
[SPEAKER_02] Yeah, no problem.
[SPEAKER_00] Alright everyone, thank you for being so flexible today.
[SPEAKER_00] You have two things at your table.
[SPEAKER_00] We have a book called Ambitious Science Teaching, which is something that we're going to be looking at and reviewing and reading throughout the course of the year.
[SPEAKER_00] It's a super helpful book.
[SPEAKER_00] The other thing is kind of a scope of what we want to try to accomplish for both this year
[SPEAKER_00] And for the three days that we had here, kind of prepping for what this year is to come.
[SPEAKER_00] As you know, a big part of this is we're conducting research.
[SPEAKER_00] We do not know the answers.
[SPEAKER_00] We're trying to figure them out together as a community of learners and amazing science teachers that are really interested in bringing authentic data investigations and students' actual communities into the classroom.
[SPEAKER_00] There's more in that bin over there if you need some.
[SPEAKER_00] So we're gonna quickly go into kind of what we're trying and hoping to accomplish this year.
[SPEAKER_00] And then I'm gonna give you a few things to try to get done over the course of the next three days.
[SPEAKER_00] And just kind of lay those out.
[SPEAKER_00] So at the end of each day together, we're gonna have about an hour, a little bit more of an hour for you to kind of think, reflect, and work with someone and collaborate.
[SPEAKER_00] And so our goals this year, as they are right now, is we have a kind of creation and design goal.
[SPEAKER_00] I've talked to some of you over Zoom about this, but our goal is that teachers will collaborate on creating, to the point of a detailed outline, a unit segment that incorporates authentic data investigation cycles, place-based data, and inferential thinking.
[SPEAKER_00] Yeah, sorry.
[SPEAKER_00] Teachers will have a strong understanding of planning from ambitious science to big ideas.
[SPEAKER_00] The unit segment will help students use data to make a sense of scientific models.
[SPEAKER_00] Data analysis will tie in with the ABCs to support inferential thinking.
[SPEAKER_00] We'll talk more about that later.
[SPEAKER_00] And that unit seconds will follow a backwards design principles that align data-based inquiry to ambitious big ideas to the unit, curricula, and newer standards.
[SPEAKER_00] Any questions so far?
[SPEAKER_00] Please just, yeah, let me know if you do.
[SPEAKER_00] The next thing is a collaboration.
[SPEAKER_00] We're already doing this.
[SPEAKER_00] Teachers will establish a community of practice that are invested in authentic data inquiry, connecting science inquiry to students' interests, community, and location.
[SPEAKER_00] We're all here because we're interested in those things already.
[SPEAKER_00] This is kind of getting back to the norms that John was just talking about, though, is making sure that we're here for each other, we're working together, and just building a community of people that are really interested in the same thing and bringing this opportunity to our students.
[SPEAKER_00] And then the last one is implementation.
[SPEAKER_00] Teachers will implement at least one lesson that they design or enact one or more lessons they've experienced from other cohort members with their students.
[SPEAKER_00] And teachers will document and reflect on those lessons they implement to the future design and implementation.
[SPEAKER_00] We're really interested in this for...
[SPEAKER_00] getting feedback from y'all, and also for informing our research on what this looks like.
[SPEAKER_00] Everyone's place is different.
[SPEAKER_00] Everyone's student's different.
[SPEAKER_00] Everyone's curriculum is different.
[SPEAKER_00] But we want to make this more of a framework or heuristic that can work for many teachers in many different places and locations.
[SPEAKER_00] So those are our three big yearly goals.
[SPEAKER_00] Do we have any questions, comments, concerns that we want to air?
[SPEAKER_02] Can you please have the PowerPoint linked to the folder that we should have included?
[SPEAKER_00] Absolutely, yes.
Great.
[SPEAKER_00] All right.
[SPEAKER_00] And now what I'm going to ask you all to do over the next three days, in the time that we have, you have a checklist on the back of this.
[SPEAKER_00] We're going to ask you to choose one to three other people.
[SPEAKER_00] to collaborate with throughout the year to co-design this unit.
[SPEAKER_00] If you want to work