the production process.
I broke her zipper on the head of her hiking bag last year and she was so mad because I was like hungry and trying to get in there.
You were hungry.
Dude, I fixed it.
You can go to a cobbler and they'll fix zippers for you.
That's cool.
I should talk to you later.
Is it head started?
Hit us with your best shot.
And I really, I know we're taking you away from stuff and I really appreciate it.
It's like the stuff like this is what helps with the funding to help us to get to.
So we'll just go ahead and get started.
These are the post questions.
We're at the end of the focus group and we've got four questions.
And if you're ready, we'll get started.
Okay.
And again, the same as what I said yesterday or when we were online,
It's going to be recorded.
We're going to save it on a drive.
It's voluntary.
You don't want to answer anything.
You don't have to.
Dot, dot, dot.
OK.
So looking back now, how has your understanding of place-based education changed or deepened since participating in Project Credible?
So this is in representation.
the past few days not before the past few days yeah this is just how has it changed since our pre focus group and now were you able to participate in the free in the free one kind of kind of okay so this is okay yeah thanks yeah okay okay all right we repeat the question now that we're on the same page yeah
So looking back now, how has your understanding of place-based education changed or deepened?
I feel like I've gotten a lot of ideas from the Tremont folks about how to make some more open-ended ideas to invite the kids to connect with their place, wherever they are.
We had some ideas already using the Level Up Challenge, sound mapping.
They just so.
I think I've truly benefited.
As.
Becoming in as teacher leaders already knowing what.
The.
not the whole end goal, but having an idea of the end goal.
I think I've mostly benefited from the people that are here learning beside us, because we have to keep it in mind that we're all at different points through this process.
And some of their fresh insights, I like thinking about where does that fit in the whole cycle of things.
So I think that's kind of helped me think more about like place-based and using
how do we connect what we've done in the past to where we're going.
I don't know if there's anything new, but yeah, I think I've gotten a lot out of the collaboration part and it might even be something I do already, but this person has a different nuanced way of doing it that I've benefited from.
The other part is being the teacher leaders and being middle school and high school, doing a similar biodiversity plot, because I've done the hula hoops before, but then seeing it done on a middle school or a high school level with the Simpsons index, and then going back just now and seeing how we can even incorporate some of that and adding a few more layers
You got anything, Mike?
I think being here, kind of immersing ourselves in both connecting to this place by just exploring it and using a lot of ways in which we can explore through tactically and listening and using our senses.
And then also the collaboration piece, being immersed with people
I think Jen and I, we were just talking about like how this is different from like some of the other PDs we've been to and how, I don't know, like how like more productive it kind of is set up like in a multiple day immersive experience because like we're really gonna know one another but also like
we plan on using it and I think intentions like with a day PD is to use it but there's like there's not a lot of time to reverse and like like being here away from home leaves us like without some of those other duties that may take up more of our time and space in our head you know when we're planning so yeah I think I realized like how unimportant names are while being here
and thinking like I've always kind of like said that but like I always want to know the name.
But now I'm just thinking like when I introduce myself to people I'm not even gonna say my name.
You're not gonna get my name, you'll get it later.
And I hear a lot of it's about like being able to collaborate into work and we've learned a lot of new kind of techniques and ways to deepen our stuff, yeah.
How is your thinking or comfort level with teaching data literacy or working with data evolved during this PD?
I think that it's less daunting.
And I think that was a big goal was to try and make it less daunting and let the tools kind of do the work for us and also realizing that data isn't just spreadsheets.
I think that's good.
I don't know.
Yeah, like I think a lot of conversation we've had about data as it's come up has been really enlightening.
Like really giving more weight to qualitative data too.
So I think yeah like and the guidance of some of the data science folks at UT has really like they've asked the questions that like kind of opened my mind up to like thinking about data being like way more broad than the narrow kind of perspective I had before.
And it's a little dry and boring.
And I think the way, I mean, that's my perception.
I think that's probably your bias.
That's definitely my bias.
And I think being here and seeing it done in a different light, like I know some of these trees, I mean, I've done been with Tremont for awhile, so.
But having that side-by-side data collection and graphing, I think that is different and new.
And it makes it less daunting and then also gives more of a relationship to these numbers in a more concrete way instead of just this abstract idea that we're supposed to be doing it.
But I think this weekend has really reinforced multiple times throughout all the sessions about, OK, how are we going to get kids to care and relate to it?
We've seen this done so many times this week.
That's been beneficial for me.
Can you share any ways you plan to use what you've learned here in your teaching?
So anything specific?
I think that CodeApp is way more, like when I first used it like five or six years ago, I liked it okay, but I think it's way more, it has a lot more useful tools now.
And I still like data classroom, but I think that CodeApp might be a little bit more for my ESS kids and still being able to create those good graphs with those standard deviation bars and all that.
So that was one for me.
to end up taking that, because I can see my standards, my sixth grade standards, turn into your ESS standards.
And like hearing that there's a wildlife, that's crazy.
And my kids could take a wildlife.
It's really helped my kids.
What could they do instead of like, I know they can do this, what could they do?
Like how could we expand this a little bit?
And I like that you said that too because a lot of times, we've talked to lots of students in the past and we've mentioned it here is that students are like, well, I don't like science.
And we're like, where did that disconnect go?
And so trying to catch that along the way is good.
And working on these standards that we plan to teach, I know we will do that.
And I work with them.
They're in the same building.
And we've had three days to hash out ideas.
And then referencing back to the BD thing, what BD have we ever had?
call Josh so he can make that data set for us if we really need it or when hearing you say like we talked this morning when we're looking at the leaves and hearing Whitaker say my seventh graders don't know what a heterotrope is and hearing you say my eighth graders don't know what a heterotrope is okay well I taught them that in sixth grade and Allie taught them that in seventh grade so how do they get to eighth grade and they still don't know that obviously speaks
So that hearing that hearing John talk about that really shifted my life Oh change here if you can learn this for three straight years and still get to eighth grade and
We're really saying it two times because they don't really have to use that language in eighth grade.
They're only saying it two times in their entire experience.
That's not enough.
That language needs to be throughout.
You're really going to learn that scientific language.
They need to have something confident attached to it and use it their own selves instead of just us telling them.
I don't know what else to add.
I think the motivation piece is pretty big.
I think I'm gonna start off with some sensory stuff this year.
What were you gonna say?
No, I think the sensory and then like the language and immersing them in visuals and hands-on versus
this is what it is, and this is what it is.
And I think you already do that with all of your observation and everything at the beginning.
So I think this might just enhance that more, because I think you already do it.
Actually, I've been talking to Josh more about incorporating secondary data yesterday morning after we were talking, and then we were sitting together.
And I think that's something I want to
focus more on, too, is how to find data so that I can use it.
When we're looking at iNaturals, how do I get this longitude latitude thing to work out?
So I think that's something that maybe I won't use, I plan to use in my classroom, but it's really kind of motivating me to learn more about.
Because it is not easy to find data across different sources even.
Good data.
Even though there's so much available,
Yeah, right?
I think part of that too is like, it's like every disciplinary area speaks a different language in every computer system, you know, so it's not this nice user friendly kind of wading through the weeds.
Yeah, find what works.
And this connects to this like, and I think we've already said a lot about what were your biggest takeaways from this specific professional development.
You all have talked a lot about that interwoven with the other questions.
Is there anything you want to add about that?
Any takeaways from the whole thing, which she said we already did.
Anything you wanna add?
I just think it's so important to have time to do this.
And I know it takes money, and that's why our district doesn't do it.
But I think what I could say is our district does not do a good job of this, right?
And we need it.
Especially with these upper-level standards and the conceptual connection between them all, it's hard to do that.
without really, maybe you were exposed to it in a mathematics class in college like 30 years ago, but it's really tough to learn when you don't know stuff, and I think this has given me the opportunity to know stuff and design really well things and have support while doing it, so it's not just me in the dark.
And I feel a lot of the cohort kind of feels that same way.
Yeah.
Totally, and that collaborative piece, and yeah.
and just being able to actually take the time to do it, yeah.
Because our district, yeah, they don't do the things.
And you guys write grants all the time and all that just to be able to do things.
And without it, then we just do the best we can.
Yeah.
I think there's a lot of that feeling I have is just like, well, I'm just going to do it day by day.
What I can is what I can.
And it's left at that.
And so having a more intentional PD like this where we're financially
But that's it's like we got here already with the mindset of like we want to make something happen this school year The only complaint I've heard is I'm tired and hot there's been nothing else.
Yeah, that's beautiful.
Yeah like
I think that speaks to like really targeting certain teachers too that would be receptive to this and trying to win them over first.
Through the project.
Yeah.
Through the teacher leaders.
Yeah, like maybe that's something we could do is like when we go DLD day, target certain people we see in some of these sessions and be like, well, you seem like you'd be down with us, right?
And that you're open to learning.
That's what I said to the person that we were out here too is,
And I said, you're open to it.
That's why you're here, you know?
And we don't wanna just hear the excuses all the time.
Just do it.
Well, maybe John was experiencing something.
Maybe delete that from the tape.
No, we're good.
I think it's just positive all around and it's just been good.
Well, that's it.
Thank you.
Any questions?
Let me know.
What kind of chips we got?
We got those hot and hotter.
You liked those ones.
Yeah, the zappos.
Yeah, I want that mild.