Tell you're recording because then... Okay, it is.
Yeah, you're good.
We're running out of our eight minutes.
Oh, I'll just let you go, sorry.
Hello.
I want to get something different.
Okay.
So are you just tossing it?
Or do we want to include any of that?
Okay, so eight minutes.
So basically nine, or not nine, 10-08.
okay okay so we just write down as many do we want to do we have to identify them or just pick them i know that he said both and he was like a through e or something of the sort is five here you want to write them down okay moss i want to say this is strawberry wild strawberry um
That might be nimblewill, but this is not.
This is maybe a sedge.
And then this is a different type of grass.
This is plantain.
Do you know what this is?
I'm not a plant girl.
I'm actually astounded by all the stuff you pulled already and was able to name.
Clover.
This is another type of grass.
They just come up.
This is another type of plant.
It's like a creeping plant.
This little buddy I think is different as well.
we just we're not going for numbers we're just going for types yeah so it had for an example they had a through f then we can use i naturalists
Different types of moss.
This one, there's two types of moss.
There's this moss and then there's like this one.
Did you get the, this one?
Is it a plantain?
Self heal?
Yeah.
This is a plantain.
Ooh, what's in that?
Oh, they count.
It's gonna be a fungi.
It's a fungi.
Okay, this is not confident.
We broke the system.
This is also different.
This is a different type of moss thing.
You can take from my pile and identify them too.
This won't focus on it.
Yeah, I won't focus on it.
It's okay.
Michelle, are you guys good?
Oh, we're good.
Okay.
We're done?
Can we come back?
I thought we had eight minutes.
Well, you were all gonna go.
Ready?
Okay.
Artifacts, stay where you are.
So when I watch you, can you guys all hear me?
Yes, sir.
So this is what I want everybody to do now.
I want you to look at your artifacts, and I want you to make observations on each one.
Don't bother giving it a name yet, right?
I don't like the look of it.
I'm just trying to describe and discern the difference between the samples we collected.
Write a little heat description for each, okay?
And if you want, you can name it.
But that will change as we get a group consensus after this.
Okay, group consensus.
Oh, wait.
You guys got a map to set on?
Yeah, that would be most appreciative, thank you.
Where can you write this at?
I just put it in your- Ohhhh.
You left it up there.
Yep.
Okay.
Okay, so the first one I've got is our fungi living on a branch.
Are they a lichen or are they a fungi?
I think those are fungi.
It wasn't working on mine, did it work on yours?
There's also some crustose lichen on there.
Okay.
He said not to identify him.
That's just A. Okay.
We're not really focused on him, but you can if you want.
I mean, you're on a high school level.
If you want to be able to use names.
That's better.
But as we do this, it gets kind of confusing, right?
Because everyone has different samples from these spots they surveyed.
So A and then B. One second.
Let me, I'm pulling up a picture of this.
Okay.
Now it's on the stick.
Yeah.
What is it?
It's mushrooms.
Got that wrong.
Can I toss him back?
Yeah.
Okay.
I'm pretty sure that was the one that was pulled in.
Next one is a mock.
So B is
The moss, like, it's right... zominate or isome.
It's a rhizome.
Okay.
Moss.
and a little bit when you guys are done I'm going to grab the other one in the middle okay so you can grab everything okay you want us to bring our samples yeah okay so keep the samples yeah when I'm done with them I'm going to put them in everything okay see if this is the same thing see are we just going to do a through f or are we wanting to do all of them I'm going to try to do all of them okay he's rushing me
So this one's the same thing.
So moving on to C, which is in the grass family.
It's like one minute.
Good.
You guys need more than a minute.
More than a minute.
More?
OK.
How's two minutes now?
I suppose I could see.
How many minutes do you need?
Two.
How many you got?
I got tons of time.
Oh.
We got like 40 minutes.
And 40.
Japanese Stiltgrass.
Uh, yes.
Okay.
So we were perfect.
what is that noise we finished and they were like
That's it, that's all you want me to do?
And I was like, okay, maybe that wasn't good enough.
So each year I've been trying to make it a little bit more complex, and I'm definitely going to try it.
Beefsteak plant.
Like beef?
Yeah, or purple mint.
Chinese basil.
Those are all common names.
It's also sick because, oh, where have you put all of our little, were you putting them back?
Oh shoot, they're all right here though.
Take them back.
They're all right here though.
hmm well you threw the one moss in there so okay then yeah we have our three samples there okay so what was beef stick again it was just beef stick something you're good oh I have okay I have all of it okay
It's just different.
I want to say this is another beef steak.
Okay.
This, wouldn't you say?
We already have that, so.
Yeah, it looks like it matches with the front.
Almost there.
White Havens.
A-B-E-N-S.
A-V-E-N-S?
Yes.
Okay.
So that should be F?
Yep.
Is that the same grass?
Somebody else though?
Oh, yep.
He just pointed at us.
Uh, Asiatic Dave?
Lay them out so everyone can see them.
If you guys are done.
If you're not done, it's okay.
Take one more minute to wrap up what you're up to.
You can do both at the same time.
Did we get enough?
We're at G, right here.
Yeah.
Well, you just said aviatic days flower.
Yeah, so more on G. This one's going to be a plantain probably.
What do we be after G?
Black seed plantain.
A, B, C, D, E, F, G, H. So you guys are probably good.
Yeah.
So black seed plantain.
okay you take that pile i'll take this okay black seed champagne plantain oh like yep got you all right time has expired
So as you guys bring over your samples, you'll be organizing and lumping them with their lights.
I think that got them wrong.
I've already laid them down.
We had, she grabbed them.
There's like four different things.
Like grasses, like super wispy mediums.
Isn't this me and others?
Yeah, my bad.
You're right.
Well, and then there's like, there's one other one.
Oh, is there a fourth one?
Okay.
Yeah, I'm sure there is.
No, I think there's one.
Okay.
Sure there is.
All right, we have all our samples.
Oh, hold on.
They're coming.
So this is a really good way to get group consensus.
By all means, you don't have to do this and collect a class or multiple class data set.
But there's a really good way to think about, regardless of what you're doing,
thinking about what kind of measurement uncertainty you're dealing with, right?
So if you're measuring stem length, where are we measuring the radical from or whatever?
So I like to group up students.
And as a group, we come up with our rules so that we all are operating under the same protocol, so that when we collect all our data, we can use it to run.
We have a higher sample size, and we run some descriptive statistics, right?
We get that delta.
So.
I think he's got his own.
I think we might have some new ones.
This one right here looks like a completely different... Yeah, we've got some... The plantain goes there.
I don't think anybody else has the strawberry.
Another reason why we chose to use the grass is because we're thinking in terms of school property, what do you have access to?
So there's many directions you could take this.
You could do like comparison between forest and lawn or just different places of the schoolyard, maybe where one area of this schoolyard gets more sun exposure, right?
Something like this.
A lot of room to differentiate.
So what we have lined up, what we're going to do again is at this level we're not going to name them.
or we will, but we're just going to name them with a letter.
Okay?
So this is where we start, right?
We have these biro fights.
Perhaps I'll grab a couple sample of these and I'll bring them to letter A so that everyone will know when they do the random sampling what letter A looks like or what species or specimen letter A is.
Do you want us to write the species for you because we identified ours?
I think for now let's not do that because it'll take a little longer because not everyone has done that.
Okay.
But the next stage of this is
Looking at species A, once we have them all lined up, we will formulate our own description for each of our specimen, creating a key.
So in classrooms where I've done this, I've actually had a big whiteboard.
And it's all on one whiteboard.
And we tape a specimen.
And we write a little description to help students along the way.
What we did just now is we extrapolated this.
And we transferred it amongst five different boards.
Could we add the names later maybe?
Yeah, you could.
Oh yeah, that's another thing too is like what a great homework exercise, right?
First you collect all the data.
Maybe the next day you want to clean up the data and you want to use their names.
Hey, perhaps at this stage everyone takes a picture of all the specimen they found and then they go home and they try to give that name to it, right?
Maybe it's genus species.
Or maybe it's just a common name.
We can give you common names.
We already did it, if you want them.
We can write them.
Either or, that's not the premise of this.
So whatever you think is best.
But the next stage here is giving each one a description.
And I think the idea behind not giving a name right away, we're all so focused on knowing a name that we forget and then take a picture of something.
But like when we began out by the friendship circle,
This is more about connecting and getting to know something through making a personal connection.
That's why the descriptors are so important.
Drawing that connection with students and stewardship in the land.
Do you mind if I add a point to that?
Someone explained it really well to me.
She said, when you meet someone, what's the first thing you usually learn about them is their name.
And then how well do you know them?
all you really know about them is their name.
So when we're teaching kids about different species, there's a lot of benefit in learning the name eventually, but it's more interesting for them to really look at the organism and say, what makes this one different from that one?
How do I know it's in this family?
What similarities, what differences does it have?
And then eventually they can learn the name.
But just knowing the name of a plant doesn't always tell you that much about those species or the surroundings or anything.
We'll play a name game later.
with people's names.
So I think at this point what we could do to continue modeling how you could do this in the classroom, can we come up with a general consensus for how to describe each of these viral fights here?
Like as a whole, how did you guys describe them in your groups?
You've already done this.
We have one, two, three, four, maybe five samples.
So we have five different unique ways of describing this.
Can we come up with a group consensus?
Low.
Low, spiky.
We got low, spiky.
Are we doing descriptions for you?
Yeah.
OK.
Green.
Soft.
Soft and spiky?
Well, spiky shape.
Yeah, that's soft.
Yeah, that's OK, right?
Kind of feathery.
Yeah.
Maybe feathery more than spiky.
Yeah, yeah.
Feathery or leafy?
So these two grasses are different than those grasses.
Okay.
Does that sound good to us?
Okay, then we move on to the next one.
How would you describe this plant?
So we have three leaves.
What else do we have?
White flowers.
Fibrous roots.
Green.
Say that the leaves are circular.
Yeah, nice.
Anybody else say something and we didn't hear?
Feel free to keep up.
And if we look closer, I think like spreads being a rhizome.
Yeah, we could get into like the science stuff that students already know, right?
Spreads.
And then, like, I think something else, like, you know this is clover, but how do you know it's clover by that, like, white little marking, right?
That's the type of clover, yeah.
Lots of clovers.
So, that's that leaf white marking.
Okay, so let's move the seed.
We have arugula?
Plantain.
Plantain, yeah.
Alright, let's describe it.
If you have a bug bite you can chew it up and put it on it.
Green!
Broad oval leaf.
Yeah, broad... clumps.
Yeah, little rosettes of... Rose... Do any of them have their little spikes?
I was going to say, there's some of them that have the flower coming up.
and then we could say this is flower good description and it's where where is it located is it center in the center in center of clump of leaf clump i could add that in there and
All right, what about the grass?
What about this one?
Guys, what color is it?
Green.
Tell me about the leaves.
Skinny.
Flat.
What is it called when they come off one stem?
Branching.
Branching, yeah, branching.
It's also nice to get the students to touch each one, right?
To feel like what that stem does feel like, is it round or flat?
Yes, those of you that have, we didn't have that one too.
There's a term for when the leaf is blade-like, when it's sword-like.
A bladed leaf?
No, they're...
I'm thinking of, like, gladiolas that are named after the Roman sword, but I feel like there's one that's a name for, like, the blade shape of grass, but I can't.
Give it the blade shape of grass!
I had parallel things.
This one looks like... If you compare these two, right, like that one looks like you're quintessential of grass at home or something, right?
That's that blade of grass.
What's this little light thing?
Oh, we haven't done height green.
Height would be good.
That's another thing, right?
But that's something you can add in your class.
You can measure all these things too.
So these have like a V-shaped blade.
They're going to have like a vein, a sedge.
So, I mean, you can't write it back because it's named, but.
And this one almost reminds me of pine needles coming out of a little fascicle.
Yeah, it does.
I mean, I know it's not connected like that, but that's what that reminds me of versus this one.
You know your butterflies?
Are you looking at them right now?
OK.
What time is it?
I'm not good at butterflies, but I do like looking at them.
I went to a butterfly farm, and we learned a lot there.
OK.
Okay, so at this point I do, if it's okay, we can go back to the stuff that is included in the criteria.
So in your journals and thank you.
So make a note that A is this guy, B is this, C is this, E is this, E is this, and then any others that you may note.
You're going to diagram out your quadrat.
You're going to label where the A's are, where the B's are.
You're going to have a little data table of how many you think you can find.
And all of that is written under the criteria, and there's also descriptions and examples in there, okay?
So it's like the fourth page or something, it says criteria, and then it says examples.
You can go count first and then come back to match which type you have.
That's true too, yeah.
You don't have to.
Yeah, I think either way.
Yeah, it's just whatever else you find.
There's a lot of, well, most of ours is F. Yeah, I know.
All right, toss that hula hoop somewhere.
There's also these little tiny mats you can sit on if you don't want to get wet.
I have our picture.
We have our chart.
We had this before, but we have A through F. We have a new A through F.
And we need a circle on our... I have our circle.
So, A was our moth, right?
And we determined that our moth was all the same, so...
I mean the moss is pretty much all over it.
Yeah, mostly on that side.
Some sporadic right here.
So that's A?
Yep.
I'm just gonna make a key and make that all A. Okay, that works.
Okay.
So now we need B. So can we do F and then indicate our original number if it's other?
Because most of ours are other.
Okay.
Because ours aren't the same as everybody else's.
We also have rhomboid mercury.
which would have been another in here.
Okay, so how do we want to do this?
So we do squigglies and so the straight lines for the key.
Well, from here I mean individual plants I think.
So this is the sedge, right?
What number was the sedge or what letter was the sedge?
I didn't have the photos on my phone.
I have my phone over here.
You're good.
A.
So, oh that's F. Gotta go backwards.
So A is the moss, we did that.
Drew it already.
G is... B is... Clover.
Do you see any clover?
We had clover, we plucked the clover.
Here's some clover.
Tiny bit there.
Where's yours?
I just see yours.
Hold on.
There's some here.
Here.
That's it?
I think so.
Oh, there's a bee.
Oh.
Yep.
This is a tiny one.
Maybe there.
One right here.
Just a tiny one.
Okay.
So A.
B. C is plantain.
So this is plantain.
So C, C, C, C, C. Did you get this?
in a second.
Okay.
Moving in that direction.
Would you say this is the same?
It is smaller.
Wasn't that self-heal?
What's our letter self-heal?
So that's F of what?
We had self-heal as D previously.
F of D. F of D!
And then there's a nice big C here.
I guess that's kind of here.
Yeah, on the border of the moss.
Here.
Was this self-heal too?
So F of D. F of D. And that's self-heal.
F of D. Plantain over there, right?
So that's C. Moving back across.
Plantain here.
I'm only writing self-heal because it's similar to... That be self-heal?
And do they compete?
And there's a sea there.
Okay.
Do you want to do flat branching?
Oh, is that the crabgrass?
Do we have any crabgrass?
We shouldn't have.
I didn't write that down.
Is this crabgrass?
We may not have grabbed it initially.
This one?
Yeah, let's see.
I mean, it would be logical for us to have crabgrass.
We have bluegrass.
I don't see crabgrass in ours.
So we'll leave that one out.
Our broad one is bluegrass.
Our broad one is bluegrass?
Yeah.
Our broad grass is bluegrass.
And bear sedge.
And whatever this is.
Japanese stiltgrass.
So we have grasses, but we don't have crabgrass.
So we can't mark that one.
E was the sedge.
Do you want to draw on the sedge?
How are we going to... E?
I can do it.
So yeah, E's are like around here.
E, E. There's a lot of... So this is the sedge?
Yes.
There's a little E there.
There's some here.
You got these already.
Okay.
Really we don't have that much more.
It's in the sunny area.
What did you list as D?
Do we even have D?
That's the one we didn't have, right?
Because we had a lot of the F. D was the crabgrass, which we didn't have.
Okay.
E was the sedge.
F is other.
Yep.
So, which one was our stiltgrass?
Stiltgrass.
F of what?
So this is stiltgrass.
What did you give it as a letter?
From the previous one?
Yeah.
Japanese soul.
That was C, previously.
So that's C there, and a lot up at the top.
What did we call our bread?
We had bluegrass, so what was our letter for bluegrass?
Do we have bluegrass?
Mm-hmm.
Might have been one of our bottoms.
That was probably the last one you mentioned and I didn't get to write it down.
So N?
Okay, yep.
F of N.
What was strawberry?
Mock strawberry?
Did you get it?
I. I?
Yeah.
F of I. F of I. We have a lot of strawberry.
Other things you notice that you want to write down that we should have a lot of, that we wrote on our thing.
You already got the self-heal, right?
Yes, we got the self-heal.
Okay.
Because that was so similar to plantain, we wrote it down at the same time.
um beef stick did we do that which one was that i don't know or did we pluck it we plucked it i know for sure because that's the one we wrote about i think it's these what letter was that beef stick was or beef steak was e f of e yeah i have two up here f of e's
Yep, that one.
Yeah, this one's been pulled.