[SPEAKER_09] So Josh, is the goal to have a place-based curriculum ready for 2033?
[SPEAKER_09] That's our next adoption.
[SPEAKER_07] 2033, so it's eight years.
[SPEAKER_09] But in eight years, I think you could do a curriculum.
[SPEAKER_09] Like, I think it would be good to sell one to all of Tennessee.
[SPEAKER_09] Well, and if you could integrate them with chemistry and biology, they're all going to be readopted in 2033.
[SPEAKER_09] And I think place-based education is good for the kids.
[SPEAKER_09] But we're going towards these storyline-based things.
[SPEAKER_09] The problems that we have is they don't have a lot of labs in them, the one that we purchased, which is making the kids actually get out and do less.
[SPEAKER_09] But they're doing less.
[SPEAKER_09] It's all paperwork.
[SPEAKER_09] And that's not good for kids.
[SPEAKER_09] I got it.
[SPEAKER_09] I just had the wrong thing selected.
[SPEAKER_09] Like I know I knew how to do this.
[SPEAKER_09] Okay.
[SPEAKER_09] collaboration in co-design?
[SPEAKER_12] Can you just swap them?
[SPEAKER_09] No, no, no, we're not staying in the friendship circle.
[SPEAKER_10] Yes.
[SPEAKER_09] Yeah, we're going into a river.
[SPEAKER_09] Which, but I mean.
[SPEAKER_04] Leave the poncho behind and just commit to it.
[SPEAKER_04] And just go swimming.
[SPEAKER_07] Multiple times this week I've gotten that little pew pew.
[SPEAKER_00] We're high enough in the mountains, we're not.
[SPEAKER_00] We're uphill.
[SPEAKER_09] So those lab safety things were driving me nuts.
[SPEAKER_09] The day I was doing it, it kept on click.
[SPEAKER_09] I'm like, I got to the point where I took a picture of the answer that I put and then pushed submit because I couldn't get one to stay.
[SPEAKER_09] And I submitted my answer and them telling me that it was the right answer because I could only get a 90 on that one.
[SPEAKER_09] I think it's like number three.
[SPEAKER_06] However many times you have to take it to get 100 but made me look like an idiot that I took it four times to try to get this 100 when I was getting it right every time.
[SPEAKER_12] I had them make the graph that the data table together and then I put it in
[SPEAKER_00] Okay, that's cool.
[SPEAKER_12] That's cool, art and data, okay, that's cool.
[SPEAKER_12] How many of you, I know some of you used it last year, how many of you used Code App at all with the students before?
[SPEAKER_12] This last year, Jen last year, cool.
[SPEAKER_12] Any other tools that you've used around,
[SPEAKER_06] Yeah, it's easy for them to get lost.
[SPEAKER_10] know what we get.
[SPEAKER_12] I'm super energetic.
[SPEAKER_09] Allison was asking about Excel, but kids don't have it.
[SPEAKER_12] Right.
[SPEAKER_12] And very similar to Google Sheets.
[SPEAKER_12] Pretty much.
[SPEAKER_10] Google's getting there.
[SPEAKER_10] Google's trying to get there.
[SPEAKER_10] It's the shortcuts that's different, really.
[SPEAKER_10] Shortcuts.
[SPEAKER_10] But you can input your own shortcuts into Google Sheets, though.
[SPEAKER_10] So it's pretty useful.
[SPEAKER_12] Yeah.
[SPEAKER_12] So how about this, if you wanna go.
[SPEAKER_09] It's all going in there all that just makes my soul happy
[SPEAKER_09] I love that.
[SPEAKER_09] Right?
[SPEAKER_09] And then so they could all see it.
[SPEAKER_09] Like, if your grade band was all studying, like, you want our butterflies, everybody goes out on this day.
[SPEAKER_09] That's crazy, Mom.
[SPEAKER_09] Yeah.
[SPEAKER_09] But if you had a curriculum that we all shared that Tennessee adopted that was play-spaced and data-driven.
[SPEAKER_09] They should be able to fit it in there if they wanted to.
[SPEAKER_09] Right?
[SPEAKER_09] Like, think about storylines.
[SPEAKER_09] Everybody's doing it.
[SPEAKER_09] We could make this more interactive.
[SPEAKER_06] And it doesn't matter if you're inner city.
[SPEAKER_09] You're representing the city demographic.
[SPEAKER_09] And you can, whatever bugs, you identify everything that you see that day at your school.
[SPEAKER_09] And so does every other school.
[SPEAKER_09] And then the next day, everybody goes back.
[SPEAKER_09] And you could see the difference between Farragut and West, or Farragut and Nashville,
[SPEAKER_09] He said that wasn't part of his plan.
[SPEAKER_09] Just giving resources.
[SPEAKER_03] Want to write a curriculum?
[SPEAKER_09] But a series of Tennessee wants to adopt something that a new teacher can just pick up.
[SPEAKER_03] Which is scripted and it's killing me.
[SPEAKER_09] Poor Allison.
[SPEAKER_09] She came to the opening training with me.
[SPEAKER_09] And she's like, doesn't that take all the art out of teaching?
[SPEAKER_09] And I'm like, I feel so good.
[SPEAKER_10] I graduated from UT in December of 2022.
[SPEAKER_05] So I came in right whenever they were wrapping up the standards that we were on board.
[SPEAKER_10] And I was like, oh, so this is what it's like to be a teacher.
[SPEAKER_09] Well, I moved here two years ago.
[SPEAKER_09] They gave us pre-AP.
[SPEAKER_09] And so I was the first one to teach it.
[SPEAKER_09] I went through it all.
[SPEAKER_09] I added things in for the implementation, lined up all the notes.
[SPEAKER_09] And then they go and change editions.
[SPEAKER_09] And this one's so scripted.
[SPEAKER_09] And the stuff we learn here is so cool.
[SPEAKER_09] And to not be able to implement any of it hurts.
[SPEAKER_09] So I'm in mornings.
[SPEAKER_09] But I think this group could write a group.
[SPEAKER_09] And write one that went from middle school through high school.
[SPEAKER_09] So what you do builds on what we do.
[SPEAKER_09] Like they're doing all this research.
[SPEAKER_09] I feel like it should go into curriculum planning.
[SPEAKER_09] And I agree that it should just be lessons to implement that all go together.
[SPEAKER_09] I mean, I like the idea of a phenomenon that leads all the instruction and the kids finding out things and problem-based learning.
[SPEAKER_09] to like the science of the moment, like what the kids asked.
[SPEAKER_09] Like there's no leeway in what we've got right now.
[SPEAKER_09] And I swear if they'd chosen to stickleback fish, like my kids would want to like jump off the bridge.
[SPEAKER_01] Because six weeks talking about a stickleback fish, we can't leave.
[SPEAKER_10] I have like 15 lessons worth, and there's sometimes more than one day for each lesson about bath bombs.
[SPEAKER_09] Getting them through the full period.
[SPEAKER_10] there goes a little too much into it.
[SPEAKER_10] A lot of these kids already know what an atom is, or they know what molecules are.
[SPEAKER_10] Whenever we're talking about platforms, we have to sit there and not say the word atom or molecule.
[SPEAKER_09] It's word we earn.
[SPEAKER_00] Kitem.
[SPEAKER_10] Kitem has organized all of our content into one platform, but it's all of the sci-ed stuff, like storylines and everything.
[SPEAKER_10] But they've just organized it into Kitem, and we're supposed to be getting these workbooks for them to work out of.
[SPEAKER_03] And I...
[SPEAKER_10] that they were going to be giving us them.
[SPEAKER_10] My thing is I would like to see it now and they haven't given us a copy of what the students will look like.
[SPEAKER_10] All I have is two teachers editions for the first unit and the second unit.
[SPEAKER_10] They haven't given us anything else.
[SPEAKER_01] think it's just
[SPEAKER_10] They really enjoy seventh grade science.
[SPEAKER_10] That's where you see a lot of their growth.
[SPEAKER_10] Wednesday the other two science teachers from my grade at my school are meeting
[SPEAKER_08] He's the one that keeps sneaking in little projects.
[SPEAKER_08] I'm like, stop it, man.
[SPEAKER_08] He's just a little scattered, I think.
[SPEAKER_08] Yeah.
[SPEAKER_04] He's got a seven-year-old kid.
[SPEAKER_08] I mean, I get it.
[SPEAKER_08] I met him during.
[SPEAKER_08] I was still like, seriously?
[SPEAKER_08] Come on.
[SPEAKER_08] Just open them all up at the beginning of the semester.
[SPEAKER_08] And the other teacher I have, I opened them all up, but she has a really strict policy.
[SPEAKER_08] You can turn it.
[SPEAKER_08] Do them all ahead of time, just don't submit them.
[SPEAKER_09] You would also probably enjoy their fishy climate training.
[SPEAKER_09] Drag it over to Nick's new because it's gigantic and I don't
[SPEAKER_09] He's just gonna accumulate stuff.
[SPEAKER_05] So yeah, take the time, drag everything you don't use.
[SPEAKER_02] I don't really have an idea who this is, but what I love, and I say this to my staff, is the norms are great, and almost everybody can come up with a good set of norms.
[SPEAKER_02] The living within those norms is tricky, because oftentimes, and one of our usual norms is, take ownership over the impacts that you have.
[SPEAKER_02] And usually everyone's like, of course I do that, but you don't always know the impacts that you have.
[SPEAKER_02] And sometimes you can hurt somebody's feelings, never know that you did, because you certainly didn't intend to.
[SPEAKER_02] But something you said or a way that you said it caught somebody wrong.
[SPEAKER_02] And in those moments, you'd never know.
[SPEAKER_02] Like the person would be hurt, the person who did it would never know, and we'd all go on, and the system remains the same.
[SPEAKER_02] But in our situation, and what I like about our staff and what I like about this group already is,
[SPEAKER_02] sharing that sense that I got my feelings stepped on, or this happened and I just wanted to bring it up.
[SPEAKER_02] So it came to me.
[SPEAKER_02] And so I just want us to know, this stuff is happening.
[SPEAKER_02] And we don't mean it, and we don't intend it, typically.
[SPEAKER_02] So.
[SPEAKER_02] Really focus on how we respond to things how we talk about things language that we use and
[SPEAKER_02] Don't sit there.
[SPEAKER_02] Don't suffer.
[SPEAKER_02] Don't think, oh, it's just because of this or that, or they didn't mean it, so I'm just not going to say anything.
[SPEAKER_02] If you had that moment, just say it.
[SPEAKER_02] I mean, this is probably the most friendly group of people you're going to work with.
[SPEAKER_02] I mean, these are people that really want to do the best by everybody.
[SPEAKER_02] So this is how we learn.
[SPEAKER_02] And this is what happens in classrooms.
[SPEAKER_02] We're going to be working together all afternoon, all evening, tomorrow, and then hopefully later on after we leave here.
[SPEAKER_02] And I want everybody to feel good about ourselves.
[SPEAKER_02] This is not like, this is not John's calling somebody else.
[SPEAKER_02] He's just recognizing that somewhere along the line, we didn't quite live up to our boundaries.
[SPEAKER_02] But maybe, I mean, we may spend a little more time even in the next couple of days just unpacking, like what does this look like?
[SPEAKER_02] What does this look like when it doesn't happen?
[SPEAKER_02] Have you ever had it happen that you got something hurt and the person didn't know?
[SPEAKER_02] They didn't know?
[SPEAKER_02] Were you able to bring it up?
[SPEAKER_02] Was there enough safety there to bring something?
[SPEAKER_02] Like that's tricky.
[SPEAKER_02] I'm just glad to know that this is that kind of place.
[SPEAKER_02] So these are sitting over there.
[SPEAKER_02] We wrote them down.
[SPEAKER_02] What time do you think that will end up being?
[SPEAKER_02] We'll take another look at the weather then.